本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  平常石头  平常迷  小蛮腰  彼岸荼蘼  平常贝
请做好下船准备
Please prepare to exit the ferry.
翻译  平常豆  平常豚  平常珞  平常髻  天朝心想上孔雀
甲板上的各位请注意
Attention on deck.
我们即将抵达火岛松林
We are now arriving at Fire Island Pines.
欢迎各位光临火岛
Welcome to Fire Island, everybody.
翻译  平常紫玉  平常小英  平常艾  平常狗  平常嘻
下船时请小心
Please take care exiting the boat.
台阶湿滑
Those steps can be wet.
另外请带齐您的随身行李
Also double-check you have all your luggage...
翻译  平常盆  平常七  平常王月  平常包  鸟爱森的温暖心
时间轴   森爱鸟的平常心   平常贝   讷讷   平常包
祝各位玩得愉快
Have a good day.
后期&特效  平常新     总监&校对  somehacker
-威克斯  -亲爱的
- Hey, Weeks. - Hey, honey.
你好吗
How you doing?
我们好着呢
We're doing great.
到了
Here we are.
你们干嘛呢
What are you guys doing?
现在不流行胸毛了  下个就是你  泰迪熊
Hairy is out. Your turn, Teddy Bear.
不要  我喜欢毛茸茸的
Oh, no, I love my Teddy.
卡尔文·克莱因可不喜欢呢
Calvin Klein would not approve.
棒球赛开始了
Baseball game is on
意味着我的夏天也正式开始了
and my summer has officially begun.
问题是  他真是这么想的
The thing is, he actually means it.
-宝贝  -你好吗
- Hey, baby. - How are you?
-要冰啤酒吗  -不用了  我已经喝了两罐了
- Cold beer? - No, I've already had a couple.
军衔很高呀  中尉  厉害
Nice stripes, Lieutenant. Hot.
拜托  上尉
Oh, please -- Captain.
刚从预备部队回来
Just got back from the Reserves.
我每个月能做一次真男人
You know what they say, once a month I get to play a real man.
最近没怎么健身嘛
Oh, haven't seen you at the gym lately.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
-到你了  布鲁斯  -到我干嘛了
- Your turn, Bruce. - What? What?
布鲁斯  拜托  别让我们在沙滩上丢脸  亲爱的
Brucey, please, don't embarrass our house at the beach, hon.
这下非去不可了
Uh-oh. Gotta do it.
奈德  你知道  俗语有云
You know what they say, Ned.
如果你无法战胜他们
If you can't beat 'em...
那就加入他们
join 'em.
这就是我男人
That's my guy.
克雷格知道你没兴趣时难过死了
Craig was miserable when you weren't interested.
可他有罗伯特·雷福德呢
Now look. He's got Robert Redford.
果然老天有眼
Shows you there is a God.
-约翰怎么样  -约翰
- How's John? - John?
-约翰  -约翰  约翰啊
- John. - John? Oh, John.
不行  我现在跟格里高利在一起呢
No, I'm with Gregory now.
庆祝在一起15个月整
We're celebrating our 15-month anniversary.
15个月  这对你来说可真是够久的  米奇
15? That's a long time for you, Mickey.
拜托  虽说我们是恋人  而且还同居了
Oh, please, we're lovers and we live together.
但这不代表我们就要对彼此忠贞
It's not like we're faithful to each other, too.
他都不是犹太人  别告诉我的拉比
He's not even Jewish. Don't tell my rabbi.
天啊
My God.
威克斯  你逊爆了
Hey, Weeks, you suck.
你还跑这来干吗
Why do you even come here anymore?
我们不想见到你
We don't want you.
你在小说里把我们写得不堪入目
You made us look terrible in your novel.
你环顾一下四周  性是自由的
Look around you. Sex is liberating.
我只是说越是乱性就越难找到真爱
All I said was having so much sex makes finding love impossible.
你自己找不到对象
Do not put your failure to find someone
-别怪我们  -奈德
- on the rest of us. - Neddy!
天啊
Oh, jeez.
Oh, God.
伙计们
Guys!
发生什么事了
Hey, what happened?
-你没事吧  -我没事
- You okay? - I'm okay.
只是有点头晕眼花
Just got a little lightheaded.
我能站起来  没事的
I got myself up. I'm fine.
只是有点头晕
I just got a little dizzy.
他看起来没事
He seemed okay.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
生日快乐
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
生日快乐
祝你生日快乐  亲爱的克雷格
Happy birthday, dear Craig
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
-吹吧  -这可是他的拿手活
- Blow.  - He's good at that.
我他妈的爱死这里了
I fucking love this place!
当我们
When we're
在舞池里翩翩起舞
On the dance floor
我能感觉到
And I feel
感觉到你的身体
And I feel your body
我知道  我的爱人
And I know my love,
让我觉得
Make me feel
你令我觉得
You make me feel
奈德  奈德
Ned! Hey, Ned!
来吧  求你了
Come on. Please?
无比真实
Mighty real
你令我觉得
You make me feel
无比真实
Mighty real.
41位同性恋者突患罕见癌症
平常心
我以前在布利克街的法国公馆
I sold you a ceramic pig once
卖过你一只陶瓷猪
at Maison France on Bleecker Street.
我是桑福德
I'm Sanford.
对啊  我记得你
Yes, I remember.
你是我一个爱收藏猪的老朋友
Somebody I was friends with then collected pigs
你那里的那只假猪
and you had the biggest pig I'd ever seen
是我见过最大的
outside a real pig.
这些玩意越长越大
They just keep getting bigger
永远也好不了
and won't go away.
我是她的第二十例患者
I'm her 20th case.
其中有六名已经死了
And six of them are dead.
奈德  快到你了
Hey, Ned. Won't be a minute.
巴兹  没想到你在这工作
Hey, Buzzy. I didn't know you worked here.
下一位是谁
Who are you?
我叫奈德·威克斯
Uh, Ned Weeks.
你在《时代》发表文章后我留过言
I spoke to you after the "Times" Article.
请进  把衣服脱掉
Come in. Take your clothes off.
我只是想来问几个问题
I only came to ask some questions.
你是同志吧
You are gay, aren't you?
是
Yes.
把衣服脱了  不用紧张
Take your clothes off. Don't be nervous.
我见的男人比你多多了
I've seen more men than you have.
你的所有问题  我只能说不知道
To answer all of your questions, I don't know.
这种情况是我闻所未闻的
I've never seen or heard of anything like this.
你有过什么症状吗
Have you had any of the symptoms?
文章中提到的大部分破玩意吧
Most of the shit the "Times" said,
变形虫  淋病  肝炎什么的
amoebas, gonorrhea, hepatitis.
你是不知道性解放之后
You don't know what it's been like
人们都在做什么
since the sexual revolution.
我怎么不知道
What makes you think I don't?
有没有发烧  盗汗  体重减轻
Any fever, night sweats, weight loss?
我倒想减重  都没有
Don't I wish. No.
有没有淤青  张嘴
And purple lesions? Open your mouth.
这是一种癌症
It's a cancer.
是免疫系统一种奇怪的反应
There's a strange reaction in the immune system.
让你的免疫系统崩溃  丧失抵抗能力
It's collapsed. Won't fight.
我的大部分患者出现的症状
So the diseases most of my patients are coming down with
都是由于细菌感染
are brought on by germs
可是病原菌弱得不能再弱
that wouldn't hurt a baby.
好难对付
Ticklish.
起码这细菌在纽约很弱
At least not a baby in New York City anyway.
免疫系统是我们最不了解的系统
The immune system is the system we know the least about.
我听说你是出名的大嘴巴
So where's this big mouth I hear you've got?
-大嘴巴也是症状吗  -不
- Is big mouth a symptom? - No.
是治疗手段
It's a cure.
这病好像只在同志圈里有
This seems to only be happening to gay men.
巴兹说你在同志圈里很有名气
Buzzy says you are well-known in the gay community
畅所欲言  毫无畏惧
and not afraid to say what you think.
没人来领导同志群体
I can't find any gay leaders
我也联系了同志组织  可是没人回应
and I call gay organizations, no one ever calls me back.
布鲁克纳医生
Dr. Brookner,
但凡有点脑子的人
no one with half a brain
都不会插手同志政治
gets involved with gay politics.
因为没有批判的权利
There's no room for criticism.
你要批判什么
What's your criticism?
我受够了总是扮演受害者
I hate that we play victim
其实我们中的很多人
when many of us,
甚至大多数人  都不至如此
most of us, don't have to.
现在需要的就是你这样的人
Then you're exactly what's needed now.
也许他们只是在等待
Maybe they're just waiting for
等待有人出来领导他们
someone to lead them.
我可不想当这个领导
I don't want to lead them.
你到底想让我干什么
What exactly are you trying to get me to do?
告诉同志们别乱搞了
Tell gay men to stop having sex.
你觉得这种癌症是通过性交传染的吗
Do you think that this cancer is sexually transmitted?
没错  我是这么觉得
I think it is, yes.
我现在能不能证明  不能
Can I prove it yet? No.
你有没有意识到
Do you realize that
你把矛头指向了上百万的人
you're talking about millions of men
他们都把乱交
who have singled out promiscuity
当成政治理想一般的存在
as their principal political agenda?
这你要怎么处理
How do you deal with that?
告诉他们这样有生命危险
Tell them they may die.
-在哪  -大厅  大厅
- Where? - Down the hall. Down the hall!
没那么简单  复杂多了
It's not that simple. It's more complicated than that.
他们觉得性是自己的全部
They think sex is all they have.
威克斯先生  如果性交有生命危险
Mr. Weeks, if having sex can kill you,
是不是但凡有点脑子的人
doesn't anyone with half a brain
都不会乱搞了
stop fucking?
你可以走了  你没有任何症状
You can go. I'm not finding what I'm looking for here.
-在哪里  -开门
- Where? - Open up!
-在哪  在哪  -就在那屋
- Where? Where? - Right in that room.
把他抬到桌子上
Just put him up on the table.
就是这儿  测下脉搏
Up here. Let's find a pulse.
放轻松  宝贝
Baby, easy.
-平静下来  -能告诉我发生了什么吗
- Be still. - Can you tell me what happened?
我们在外面等他
We were meeting him outside.
拐了个弯  他就倒了下来
We turned the corner and he just collapsed.
上帝啊
Jesus!
别他妈在街上瞎晃荡
Hey, get the fuck out of the street!
亲爱的
Baby!
-天啊  -来人
- Oh, my God! - Help!
-谁是他爱人  -我是  女士
- Who's the lover? - I am, ma'am.
-你叫什么  -布鲁斯·耐尔斯
- What's your name? - Bruce Niles.
我是布鲁克纳  马上给我一间房
Brookner. I need a room immediately.
耐尔斯  你是莱因哈特的男朋友
Niles, you were Reinhardt's boyfriend.
是的  女士  你怎么知道的
Yes, ma'am. How do you know that?
他三周前去世了
He died three weeks ago.
他们不让我和他道别
Wouldn't even let me say goodbye.
都不让我和他吻别
Not even let me kiss him goodbye.
他去世了
He's dead?
节哀
So sorry.
这病能这么快致人死亡
It can happen this fast?
这不就是例子吗
It just did.
我们得做点什么
We have to do something.
别人不会关心的
No one else will.
我们该做什么
What are we supposed to do?
你只考察了46个病例就做了猜想
You make these assumptions on the basis of 46 cases.
你们想知道我的想法  我就是这么认为的
You wanted to know what I think. This is what I think.
你们会互相传染
You are all going to infect each other.
现在只有少部分人染病
Now only a few of you have.
但不幸的是我们无法辨别是谁
Unfortunately, we can't tell yet which ones.
早在分离出肝炎病毒前
Long before we isolated the hepatitis viruses,
我们就知道了病症
we knew about the diseases they caused
以及传播途径
and how they got around.
医学期刊上的文章呢  纽约时报呢
Where are the medical journals? The "Times"?
我早在一年前就把报告寄给医学杂志了
I sent my first reports to the medical journals over a year ago.
不好意思  你怎么知道你要找什么
Excuse me, how do you know what you're looking for,
就一句  不知道找什么的话从何找起呢
real quick, if you don't know what you're looking for?
不好意思  估计这问题有点蠢
I'm sorry, I guess that's a dumb question.
并非如此  这是最睿智的问题了
No, it isn't. It's the smartest question of all
也是最难回答的
and the hardest one to answer.
你们就不能稍微收敛一下吗
Doesn't common sense tell you you should cool it for a while?
为什么不呢
Why not?
那样活着还有什么劲
That doesn't leave much to look forward to.
要是最后你错了怎么办
What if it turns out that you're wrong?
让她说
Let her speak!
只是稍微收敛一下
The worst that could happen
有什么大不了的
would be that you cooled it for a while.
不对  不好意思
No, excuse me. Excuse me.
不好意思  不是没什么大不了的
Excuse me. That is not the worst that will have happened.
大家会害怕做爱
Guys will become frightened of sex.
我们会失去我们为之
We will lose our self-respect
奋斗许久的自尊
that we fought very, very hard for.
我们会成为最悲惨的替罪羊
We will be scapegoated worse than ever.
全世界都会认为我们是携带者
The world will think we're carriers
占领道德高地的人更会大放厥词
and the Moral Majority will have even more of a field day.
这坐轮椅的婊子不走我就不来了
I am not coming back until this bitch on wheels is gone.
等等  病人的数量越来越多
Wait! I see more cases each week than the week before.
一半的病人都死了
Half of all my patients die.
好了  赶紧总结一下
Okay, I hope she winds this up,
新罗谢尔还有几个帅哥等着呢
'cause I've got a tiny little orgy in New Rochelle.
卫生部呢  市长呢
Where's the health department? Where's the mayor?
-闭嘴吧  约翰  -你闭嘴吧  亲
- Shut the fuck up, John. - Oh, you shut the fuck up, hon.
人数有多少
What are the numbers?
每次同志聚会都这样吗
Is every gay meeting like this?
一半人来都是为了找人滚床单
Half these people just showed up to get laid.
安静  安静
Quiet! Quiet!
我们要成立一个小组
We're starting a group.
我们要成立一个健康危机处理小组
We're starting a health crisis group.
我们会再次在这里开会
We're gonna meet here again.
下次  带点吃的来
Next time, bring some fucking food.
这可不好
Hey, hey, hey. That's not nice.
这就是同志群体的政治
Welcome to gay politics.
这群人有了
奇怪的毛病
就是这个样子
同性癌症
痘痘一样的瘀伤  不痛不痒
疹斑一样的瘀伤
全身各处皆有
《纽约时报》
我跟克雷格·克莱本
Yeah, I'm very late for
有个很重要的会  我迟到半天了
an important meeting with Craig Claiborne.
他正在等我
He's expecting me.
-你好  菲利克斯·特纳  -你是
- Hi, Felix Turner. - And you are?
我叫奈德·威克斯
My name's Ned Weeks.
你好帅
You're very cute.
我现在很忙  明白吗
You caught me at a rough moment, all right?
马上就要交稿了  第一夫人来了
I have a deadline. The First Lady is coming to town.
我听说你是同性恋  你也许可以
I've been told you're gay and you might be able
帮我在《纽约时报》上刊登些重要消息
to help me get some vital information in the "Times."
你听说吗
You've "been told"?
听谁说的
And who was it that told you?
亲爱的  谁不知道啊
Oh, honey, everybody's talking about it.
为什么每个同志
Why does everyone gay
都以为《纽约时报》是我家的
think that I run "The New York Times"?
我帮不上忙
I can't help you with this.
深表同情  那我还能怎么办
Sorry to hear that. What would you suggest I do?
那是你的事  我还有23个党派
Take your pick. I got 23 parties,
37家新餐馆和12家新舞厅要写
37 new restaurants, 12 new discos.
听着  我跟好几个记者谈过了
Listen, I can't get anyone here to write another article.
没人肯帮我写
I've talked to half a dozen reporters
哪怕是之前写过同志题材的
and the guy who worked on the first piece.
兰德先生吗  当然不会
Mr. Leather? Yeah, no.
这里的每一个人都不会写  包括我
No one here will write about it and I can't.
我们这里有很明确的分工
Look, we're very compartmentalized.
写科学栏目的不会写羊毛衫
You wouldn't want science to write about sweaters, would you?
在这个异性恋主导的世界里
It's a very peculiar feeling having to go out
为同志群体寻求帮助是非常微妙的
and seek support from a straight world for something gay.
我怎么可能知道
I wouldn't know about that.
我一直在写同性恋设计师  舞厅
I just write about gay designers and gay discos
厨师  模特  摇滚歌手
and gay chefs and gay models and gay rock stars
以及同性恋名人  所有关于同性恋的事
and gay celebrities and gay everything.
我只是不用同性恋这个词
I just don't call them gay.
那你是不是该用这个词了
Isn't it time you start?
我真的要交稿了
Look, I really do have a deadline,
我丢饭碗对你也没好处
and you wouldn't want me to get fired.
让让可以吗
Would you?
真是受不了你这种人
Guys like you give me a pain in the ass.
-你是写书的吧  -是的
- You in the book? - Yes.
男同健康危机组织
大伙儿  帮帮同性恋癌症患者吧
Hi, guys. Give to gay cancer?
捐点钱吧  可以吗
Hi, give to gay cancer? No?
捐点钱吧
Hi. Give to gay cancer?
先生
Hi, sir.
捐点钱吧  同性恋团体需要您的帮忙
Hi, give to gay cancer? There's a cancer in the gay community.
捐点钱吧
Can you give to gay cancer?
我们的团体如今处于水深火热中
There's a... there's a crisis in our community right now.
我们急需
We could really use...
我们急需帮助  一分钱也行
We could use a little help. Anything? No?
我觉得你可以温和点
I think you could be a little less aggressive.
温和点  我们之前就是太温和了
Less aggressive? We've tried that.
能为我们的团体捐点钱吗
Can you give to cancer in our community?
捐点钱吧
Hi, give to gay cancer?
男同健康危机组织
愿意捐个款吗
Hi, give to gay cancer?
有趣的是  我妈妈还送了花
It's funny. My mother sent flowers.
我没跟她说过我是同性恋
And I had never told her I was gay.
我只说克雷格去世了
I just told her that Craig had died.
我觉得她知道
I think she knew.
妈妈们总是知道
I think somehow mothers always know.
花五百万买栋房子  吓死你了吧
Doesn't spending $5 million on a house frighten you?
让你为我理财才吓死我了
Scared the shit out of me even having you handling my finances.
你什么时候想要房子都可以
You can have a house anytime you want.
这倒提醒了我  你需要更多的钱
Which reminds me, your account needs more money.
你干得还不错
You're not doing too badly.
很怀念你干电影这一行
I miss you being in the movie business.
-我喜欢电影  -老是讽刺我的大哥
- I like movies. - Do I detect a note of approval
终于肯表扬我了吗
from the big brother that called me "Lemon"?
我不想要房子
I don't want a house.
那你为什么在乡下找了那么久房子
Then why have you been searching in the country for so long for?
-我不想一个人住  -布鲁斯
- No fun living in it alone. - This Bruce...
是你男朋友吗
is he someone you're seeing?
我对他有意思  他对我无感
I see him, he doesn't see me.
本
Ben...
你们公司能无偿帮忙吗
could your law firm take this on for free?
为公益出一份力
What's it called? Pro bono?
我们为一种新疾病成立了一个组织
We started an organization, I told you there's this new disease.
是不是你不想写书  找的新借口啊
Now this sounds like just another excuse to keep from writing.
你就不能答应我吗
Why can't you just say "Yes"?
我告诉过你  这些事
I told you, because we have a committee
要由委员会来决定
that decides that kind of thing.
但你是资深合伙人
But you're the senior partner
而我是你弟弟
and I'm your brother.
你好  马里奥  荷马还好吗
Hey, Mario. How's Homer?
如果你不帮忙  我得找别人了
If you're not gonna help, I'm gonna have to find somebody else.
你大可去找别人帮忙
Well, you're more than free to do that.
我不想弄到这种地步
I don't want to do that.
我希望我出色的哥哥
I want my big brother's fancy, famous,
一流的大牌律师事务所
big-time, major law firm
成为第一家为同性恋
to be the first straight New York law firm
提供无偿服务的纽约律师事务所
to do pro bono work for a gay cause.
我会为你骄傲的
I'd be real proud of that and you.
下次开会我去征求合伙人的意见
I'll ask my partners' approval at the next meeting.
我来游说  你好像没什么把握
I'll lobby them. You don't sound like a very sure vote.
好吧
Okay.
你的表现越来越好了
You're getting better at it.
我每周会有三到四名新患者
I'm seeing three to four new patients a week.
重症病房里有七名
I've got seven in ICU.
整个医院只能容纳三十名患者
The whole hospital only has room for 30.
我不得不以其他病因收治病人
I've had to admit some of them under other illnesses.
已经违反原则了
That's a no-no.
有二十个人住在私人病房  付不起钱
I've got 20 in private rooms they can't afford.
好吧  那些没有医疗保险的人怎么办...
Okay, what about the guys who don't have health insurance...
-艺术家  演员  -我让他们住在了
- Artists, actors? - I've got eight of them in another ward
他们不该住的另一间病房
where I shouldn't put them.
同性传播免疫缺陷疾病
你为什么不戴手套和面罩
Why don't you wear gloves and a face mask?
我从没戴过  以后也不会戴
I never have and I never will.
但我还活着
And I'm still here.
为什么食物都像这样放在房间外面
Why is all the food sitting outside their rooms like this?
-都要凉了  -每次都是凉的
- It's getting cold. - It's always cold
因为工作人员不肯送进去
because the appropriate staff won't bring it into the rooms,
没人肯送  就只好烂在这里
so it sits and rots until one of my staff can.
就从那穿过去
Right through there.
就是那  对  在水边
Right there. Yeah, by the water.
隧道就在那
The tunnel is there.
对  穿过隧道
Yeah, right through the tunnel.
从隧道走  我们要把书拿回去
Take the tunnel. We'll take the book back.
我认识他  我能跟你进去吗
I know him. Can I go inside with you?
你得戴上护具
Only if you wear all the protective shit.
你不戴我也不戴
If you don't, I don't.
就在那  走另一条路
Over there. Go the other way.
不  你在听我说吗
No, are you listening to me?
你在听我说吗  倒回去
Are you listening to me? Go back.
-桑福德  -你看到了吗  从隧道走
- Hi, Sanford. - You see that? Take the tunnel.
往前走  直接开过去
Go ahead, drive straight through.
你怎么样  小勇士
How we doing, soldier?
我想要我的狗  你能把它带来吗
I want my dog. Can you please bring me my dog?
它离了我可活不下去
He won't be able to live without me.
我要我的狗  我要我的狗
I want my dog. I want my dog.
往前走  这就对了
Go ahead. That's right.
很好  很好  不  把书拿回来
Oh, good. Good. No. Take the book back.
就在那  使劲拉
Right there. Pull hard.
就在那
Right there.
你能把我的狗带来吗
Can you please bring me my dog?
它离了我可活不了
He won't know how to live without me.
别费劲了
Don't bother.
谁能把我的狗带来
Who's going to bring me my dog?
它叫跳跳  你叫它它就会过来
His name is Skip. He'll come when you call him.
拜托了
Please.
我很想它
I miss him.
才十九岁  却变成这样
Can you imagine this at 19?
刚遇到爱人  打算共度一生
Your first boyfriend you were gonna spend your whole life with.
-不好意思  -怎么了
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
你是修电视的人吗
You're the TV guy?
请去修一下407病房的电视
Please go to room 407 and fix it.
-我不会去的  -去修  那他妈是你的工作
- No, I'm not gonna do that. - Fix the TV. It's your fucking job.
工会说  不能为了有传染病的基佬
My union says I don't gotta risk my life
把自己的命搭上
for some contagious fairy.
我必须进去吗  那我辞职
If I have to go in there, then I fucking quit.
你们的组织出力了吗
So what exactly has your side been doing?
谢谢
Thanks.
想来点这个吗  还是啤酒
Want some of this? A beer?
啤酒吧  多谢
Oh, beer's fine. Thanks.
狗狗你好呀
Oh, hey, pooch.
-它叫萨姆  -你好  萨姆
- Her name's Sam. - Hi, Sam.
我以前真的很喜欢高科技
You know, I really used to like high-tech,
但我现在已经厌倦了
but I'm tired of it now.
我真希望印花棉布能够回归
I think I want chintz back again.
无意冒犯
Don't be insulted.
没事
I'm not.
我也希望现在还有印花棉布
I want chintz back again, too.
就是这样了
So, here we are.
两个希望印花棉布重新回归的家伙
Two fellows who want chintz back again.
我猜这真的是个约会
I guess this really is a date.
我饿死了
I'm starving.
我来了你高兴吗
You glad I'm here?
高兴疯了
I'm pleased as punch you're here.
你长那么好看  何苦来这呢
You're very good-looking. What are you doing here?
你觉得自己长得不好看吗
You think you're bad-looking or something?
你是哪里人
Where you from?
俄克拉荷马
I'm from Oklahoma.
我十八岁离家  供自己...
I left home at 18, put myself through--
怎么  你想跳舞吗
What, you wanna dance?
供自己读完大学
Put myself through college.
我爸爸在西塔尔萨的精炼厂工作
My dad worked at the refinery in West Tulsa
妈妈是服务员
and my mom was a waitress.
在沃尔格林里开过小吃店
Had a luncheonette in Walgreens.
多了不起啊  一个小孩走出乡下
It's amazing, isn't it? How a kid comes out of all that
在《纽约时报》扬名立万
and wind up on the "Times",
左右着世界的品味和风格
dictating taste and style to the entire world.
你又不会好好说话了
And we were just starting to talk so nicely.
我说的话没有问题
Talking's not my problem.
只是不知道何时闭嘴
Shutting up's my problem.
你为什么总是写华而不实的舞会礼服
Why do you write all that fancy ball gown bullshit?
我打赌你每天还是会看
I bet you gobble it up every day.
死去的人里  我认识十个
I know 10 people who have died.
我找你的时候  才一个
When I came to you, it was only one.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
所以你才答应这次约会的吗
Is that why you agreed to this date?
左手拿叉
Fork on the left.
右手拿刀
Knife on the right.
你知道希特勒除掉波兰犹太人的
Did you know that Hitler's Final Solution
屠杀方案是最先在
to eliminate the Polish Jews
《纽约时报》第二十八版披露的吗
was first mentioned in the "Times"? It was on page 28.
还有《华盛顿邮报》的第六版
On page 6 of the "Washington Post."
都是犹太人经营的报纸  他们自己的族人
They are both owned by Jews. Their very own people.
学者们终于写出了
Scholars are finally writing
真实情况  却不受待见
honestly about it and it's damning to everyone.
基督教会  教皇  丘吉尔和罗斯福去哪了
Where is the Christian churches? The Pope? Churchill? Roosevelt?
他们随便说句话都能让大家警惕希特勒
A few words from any of them would have put Hitler on notice.
达豪集中营1933年建成  大家都他妈在哪
Dachau was open in 1933. Where the fuck was everybody?
今晚的气氛真是浪漫
This is turning out to be a very romantic evening.
你从来没有过爱人  是吗
You've never had a lover, have you?
我猜你爱人不少
I suppose you've had quite a few.
我有过一个非常好的
I had a very good one.
交往了很多年  谢谢夸奖
For a number of years, thank you.
他年纪比我大  又找了更年轻的
He was older than I was and he found someone younger.
你想找父亲型的吗
You looking for a father?
不  我不想找父亲型的  天呐
No, I'm not looking for a father. God.
你嘴真毒
You're relentless.
好吧
Okay.
那是你的
That's yours.
大家都有无数的理由置身事外
Everybody had a million reasons for not getting involved.
美国犹太人分明知道在发生什么
The American Jews knew exactly what was going on.
想一想  所有犹太人
Could you imagine if every
一起向华盛顿进发是什么样
Jew had marched on Washington proudly, huh?
奈德
Ned.
你不记得我了  是吗
You don't remember me, do you?
是几年前在一间浴室
It was at the baths a few years ago.
探寻"男人国度"  发现我们的实力
Come to Man's Country, see what we're all about
和呈现给您的一切
and what we have to offer.
"男人国度"是设施齐全  功能多样
Man's Country is a full facility, multileveled complex
为满足各色需求而设的场所
that was designed to feature something for everyone.
来"男人国度"健美塑身
Come to Man's Country to develop your body...
或塑造与他人的友谊
or a friendship with somebody else's.
踏进我们  您便会欲罢不能
Visit us once and you'll come again and again.
你看我的样子  让我觉得
You would've thought I was applying for the CIA
是中情局在考察我
the way you looked at me.
然后怎么了
And then what happened?
我跟着你进了隔间
I followed you into your room.
你连眼睛都不睁开
You couldn't even open your eyes.
跟我说你的真名是亚历山大
You told me your real name was Alexander.
我问你是做什么的  你说自己
I asked what you did and you said something like
"试过不少事情"  然后...
you "tried a number of things" and...
我问你试过爱别人吗
I asked if that had included love.
你回我说
That's when you said,
"我明早还要早起"
"I have to get up early in the morning."
人心里都是有爱的
Men do not naturally not love.
除非后天磨灭掉
They learn not to.
你觉得你是虚张声势
I think you're a bluffer.
我怎么会不记得你
How could I not remember you?
不知道
I don't know.
当时挺暗的
It was very dark.
你觉着我们能重新来过吗
Do you think we could start over?
我上耶鲁时  以为我是里面唯一的同志
When I was going to Yale, I thought I was the only gay guy there.
不骗你
Swear to God.
去看心理医生  他还试图改变我
Went to the shrink who tried to change me.
现在学校里都有"同志周"了
Now they have "Gay Weeks" there
办的舞会是全校最棒的
and they throw the best dances of anyone.
试想一下  你能和你男朋友
Imagine being able to dance cheek to cheek
在美好的大学时光里相拥共舞
with your boyfriend during your bright college days.
你和女人睡过吗
Did you ever sleep with a woman?
怎么
What?
她叫黛利拉
Her name was... Delilah.
黛利拉
Delilah?
她是
She was...
是我写的一部电影里的替身演员
a stand-in on this movie I wrote.
她人很好也很漂亮
She was very nice and pretty.
总是冲我笑
Always smiling at me.
我就去问我的一个直男朋友这是什么意思
So I-- I asked a straight friend to explain it to me.
其实我知道  就是想确认下
I thought I knew, but I just wanted to make sure.
我就带她去吃晚餐
And I had her to dinner and...
之后  我就在我认为合适的时间
afterwards, what I deemed to be a suitable moment
因为我一直在跟"下面"沟通
because I had been communicating with it down there--
"你准备好了吗  你真的真的准备好了吗"
"Are you ready? Are you absolutely certain you're ready?"
等到下面的小哥准备好了
And when it appeared "Abercrombie" was ready.
我抱起她  像白瑞德抱斯嘉丽[乱世佳人]一样
I picked her up, very Rhett Butler,
轻轻放到床上
and carried her to my bed,
但我却硬不起来了
where I couldn't get it up.
-但是  -这点我感同身受
- But-- - I can certainly relate to that.
大半夜里
In the middle of the night,
我醒来  下面硬的生猛
I woke up with this gigantic erection,
天知道怎么搞的
God-- God knows how.
所以我把她摇醒了  大喊
So I shake her, shouting,
快帮我插进去  黛利拉
"Please stick it in for me, Delilah."
我当时特别担心
I was afraid of it going away before I could-- -
看到关键部位会软
while I was hunting for the right place to put it.
她高潮了  我也高潮了  小哥也是
She did and I did, and Abercrombie did.
第二天早上我醒来
The next morning I woke up
想起那个神神叨叨
and I, who had been under the spell of this shrink
一心改变我的心理医生
who was determined to change me,
我就冲到他办公室
rushed into his office.
我这个从七年级
And I, who had been fucking with fellows
就跟小伙伴乱搞的人
since the 7th grade,
在三十二岁时歇斯底里地宣布
hysterically, at the age of 32 proclaimed,
"吉莱斯医生  我破处了"
"Dr. Gillespie, I'm no longer a virgin!"
他在这  我们能碰上他
He's in here. I think we'll catch him.
好吧
All right.
我就直接走上前打招呼吗
So, I just go over and say hello?
我说是我邀请你来的  耶鲁的同学
I told him I invited you and we went to Yale together.
这是我的告别派对  他能怎么做
It's my farewell party. What's he gonna do?
走吧
Let's go.
市长先生想叫你们滚蛋
His Honor would like you to get lost.
这是我朋友  奈德·威克斯
This is my friend, Ned Weeks.
我们知道他是谁
Yeah, we know who he is.
市长先生  我们需要你的帮助
Mr. Mayor! We need your help!
现在有一种新型疾病  你一定有所耳闻
There's this new disease. You must have heard about it.
我们迫切需要你的帮助  放手  蠢猪
We need your help badly! Get off me, you pigs!
这里是美国
This is America!
市长先生  我们在垂死挣扎
Mr. Mayor! We're dying!
这是奈德写给我们要寄出去的
Okay, this is what Ned wrote for us to send out.
"我受够了整天絮叨我们不要放纵
"I am sick of guys moaning that giving up careless sex..."
小心丢了性命的人
"...until this blows over is worse than death.
我受够了只关心自己下半身的人
I am sick of guys that can only think with their cocks.
我受够了不肯出柜的同志
I am sick of closeted gays.
都1982年了  同志们
It's 1982 now, guys,
你什么时候出柜  你能活到1983年吗"
when are you gonna come out? By 1983 you could be dead."
你疯了
You're crazy.
是吗  布鲁斯  你真这么觉得
Am I, Bruce? Do you really think so?
-我们今晚不是要选出主席吗  -是的
- Aren't we supposed to elect a president tonight? - Yes.
别人的生活我们无权干预  奈德
We can't tell people how to live their lives, Ned.
同志的政治就是做爱
The entire gay political movement is fucking.
其实呢  我想给病人们
You know, I'm very interested in
提供一些特殊服务
starting up some sort of services for the patients.
我们一定得谈谈这个
We've gotta start talking about them.
外面还有很多人惊慌失措
Also, there are a lot of very scared people out there
急切地想要更多信息
and they're desperate for information.
我想建立热线电话
I'd like to start a hotline.
他是谁
Who's he?
他还不知道我是谁
He does not know who I am yet.
他叫汤米·博特莱特
His name is Tommy Boatwright.
日常生活中  他是医院院务主任
In real life, he is a hospital administrator.
他是来帮忙的  还是个南方的浪荡帅哥
Uh... he's here to help and he's a Southern bitch.
博特莱特先生  布鲁斯·耐尔斯
Mr. Boatwright, Bruce Niles.
-很高兴认识你  -我的荣幸
- Nice to meet you. - My pleasure.
你可真帅
You're very handsome.
-他清楚得很  -确实很帅
- He knows.  - Yes, well he is.
这是什么鬼
The fuck is this?
这是你的主意吗  奈德
Was this your idea, Ned?
我在看  哪里有问题吗
I'm looking. What am I not seeing?
-仔细看  -寄信人地址是怎么写的
- Keep looking. - What we put for our return address.
你是指信封上有"同志"这个词吗
Do you mean because the word "Gay" is on the envelope?
完全正确  不写名字只写同志
Fucking A, yes. Instead of just our initials.
-不能寄出去  -拜托
- We can't send these out. - Excuse me.
要是还想有人来参加舞会
If we want anybody to show up for this dance,
今晚必须把这些信寄出去
we have to get these out tonight.
我们得全部检查一边
We need to go through and
用马克笔把"同志"这个词划去
scratch out the word "Gay" With a Magic Marker.
亲爱的  要划上一万次吗
Oh, honey, 10,000 times?
布鲁斯  如果是寄给跟父母一起
Bruce, I have sympathy for kids living at home
住在长岛的人是有些麻烦
on Long Island with their parents, but--
但我们的收信人  比如你
but the guys who are getting these... look at you.
你独居在家  有自己的公寓
You live at home-- you live alone, you own your own apartment,
你妈妈住在另一个州
your mother lives in another state.
那我的邮递员呢
Okay, what about my mailman?
你不是认真的吧
You don't expect me to take you seriously.
-我很认真  奈德  -姑娘们注意言辞
- Yes, I do, Ned. - Okay, ladies, behave.
已经很晚了  我们还没选出主席
Look, it's getting late and we still haven't elected a president.
奈德
Neddy...
我觉得应该选布鲁斯
I think that it should be Bruce.
大家都认识他  喜欢他  所有人...
Everybody knows him everybody likes him - and everybody--
因为他更受欢迎  而大家都怕我吗
'Cause he's popular and everybody's afraid of me?
没错
Yes!
瞧瞧他  他光彩照人
I mean, look at him. He's-- he's gorgeous
住在克里斯多福街和法尔岛的同志们
and all the kids in Christopher Street and Fire Island,
他们会更心甘情愿地
they'll just-- they'll feel  a little bit more comfortable
追随他
following him.
-就像高中时那样  -没错
- Just like high school. - Yes!
赞成布鲁斯·耐尔斯
All right, all those in favor of Bruce Niles
担任首届主席的人请举手
as our first president, raise their hands.
我还没想好当不当
I don't think I want this.
得了吧  你那么帅  谁不愿意跟你呢
Oh, come on. You're gorgeous and we're all gonna follow you.
-操你  我干了  -操你  恭喜
- Fuck you, I accept. - Well, fuck you, congratulations.
菲利克斯  我们搬去远方吧
Felix... let's move somewhere far away,
只有你我  一起待在荒岛上
just the two of us, together on a desert island.
你正在做的事情可一分一秒都不能停
Don't you dare stop for one single second what you're doing.
《纽约时报》不作为
I appreciate you not yelling at me
我也没有更积极地参与
about what the "Times" isn't doing
很感谢你没对我发脾气
and my not being more political.
你怎么不生气呢
Why don't you?
能有个人只讲雪月  不谈政治  也是种放松
It's a relief not having to have to talk politics with someone,
但不是因为这个
but that's not the reason.
不是吗
No?
因为你太美好了
It's because you're too good to be true,
我等你等了这么久
because I've been waiting for a lover like you my whole life,
才能跟你在一起
you haven't showed up until now,
我害怕得不得了
and I'm scared shitless
生怕自己搞砸了
that I'm gonna do something to fuck it up.
-我疯了吗  -当然
- Am I crazy? - Of course.
我就喜欢这样
That's why I'm here.
终于暖和起来了
Now we gettin' warm.
我看起来还好吗
Did I look okay?
能看出来我是用化妆品在遮吗
Could you tell I was wearing all this makeup?
你看起来很好
You looked great.
你得去见见艾玛
You have got to go see Emma.
能别提这档子事吗
Can we just forget about this?
我很好
I'm all right.
就算不好我也宁可自欺欺人  否则没人会雇我
And if I'm not, I don't wanna know because no one will hire me,
如果我丢掉了工作  就只能等死了
and if I can't work, I'd just as soon be dead.
我的体重没有降低
I haven't lost any weight.
我还能遮住
I can still cover it up.
-我说了别告诉他  -对不起
- I told you not to tell him. - Sorry.
已经害怕亲吻我了吗
Already afraid to kiss me?
不是这样的
That's not true.
没关系  我也不敢让你吻我
It's okay. I'm afraid to let you.
我爱你
I love you.
我送他下楼
I'll walk him down.
他是我的第三个伴侣
Okay, he's the third guy I've been with.
莱因哈特  克雷格  如果艾伯特得病
Reinhardt, Craig, and I don't know what I'll do
我真不知道怎么办
if Albert has this.
你得去战斗
You're gonna fight.
我们要一起战斗
We'll fight together.
你是我最好的朋友  奈德·威克斯
You're my best friend, Ned Weeks.
你是我最好的朋友  我从未遇见过你这样的人
You're my best friend and I've never met anyone like you before.
什么叫我这样的人
What do you mean, like me?
你这样  就是说...
Like you, meaning...
我出生长大的地方
where I'm from, I-- I mean--
我参军前  都没见过犹太人
I didn't even see a Jew until I was in the Army,
更别说这样一个
let alone a man that was
机智  风趣
smart, funny...
外表出众的男人
decently good-looking.
我的朋友都不跟我出去玩
My friends stopped hanging out with me
因为他们说我让他们感到压抑
because they say I depress them.
压抑就压抑吧
So be it.
而你...
And you...
你看起来不像那种犹太人
you don't look that Jewish.
你看起来也不像同性恋
Well, you don't look gay,
不过我们总归还都是白人
so I guess we can both pass for white people.
我爱艾伯特
I love Albert.
布鲁斯  看着我
Bruce, look at me.
我爱他
I love him.
艾伯特会挺过去的
Albert's gonna make it.
如果不能呢
What if he doesn't?
我送你回家吧
Let's get you home.
-我真是一团糟  -是啊
- I'm a mess. - Yeah.
真是优雅
Classy moment.
-我没事  -好
- I'm all right. - Okay.
我一直想在浴房抱着你
When I finally get you where I want you,
现在得偿所愿了
I don't want you anymore.
布鲁斯  我也陷入爱河了
Hey, Bruce, I'm in love too.
我操
Holy shit!
全是同志啊
Queen control.
希望梦想成真时  就真的实现了
Really works when it wants to.
菲利克斯  这是迪克·隆巴
Oh, hey, Felix. This is Dick Lombardo.
-你好  -终于来了一位
- Hi. - Finally got us someone on our board
会跳迪斯科的董事了
who isn't a disco dummy.
就今晚会跳
Well... maybe tonight.
-一会见  -很高兴见到你
- I'll see ya. - Nice to meet ya.
走吧
Come on.
很高兴今晚各位的加入
We are all so happy you joined us tonight!
我们证明了我们不止有外表
We are proving that we are more than just looks,
头脑  天赋和内心情感
brains, talent and heart.
我们比城里任何男同组织
Together we raised more than
筹集的资金都要多
any gay group ever in this city.
我想为大家介绍奈德·威克斯先生
And I wanna call over Mr. Ned Weeks.
别害羞
Don't be shy.
我们做到了
We did it!
现在来揭晓  我们一共筹集了多少钱
We will now reveal just how much we raised together.
倒数  三  二  一
In three, two, one...
53,000美元
$53,000!
男同健康危机组织的成员  快上台
Gay Men's Health Crisis, come on up.
菲利克斯  亲爱的  上台来  快上来
Felix, honey, come on up, please. Come up.
我爱你
I love you.
舞动起来
Let's dance!
某天他将到来
Someday he'll come along
那个我爱的男人
The man I love
他强壮又高大
And he'll be big and strong
那个我爱的男人
The man I love
当他向我走来
And when he comes my way
我会尽我所能
I'll do my best
让他留下
To make him stay
他注视着我  朝我微笑
He'll look at me and smile
我就心领神会
I'll understand
不久之后
And in a little while
他会牵起我的手
He'll take my hand
尽管看似荒诞
And though it seems absurd
彼此相视无语
I know we both won't say a word
或许我会在周日遇见他
Maybe I shall meet him in Sunday
或许是周一
Maybe Monday
又或许无法遇见
Maybe not
我仍然相信我会遇见他
Still I'm sure to meet him one day
想象一下如果我们年轻时  拥有此刻的场景
Imagine if we had this when we were young.
或许周二
Maybe Tuesday
无畏无惧  无所遗憾
No fear, no shame.
是我的幸运日
Will be my good news day
这些年我的梦里都是你
All I was imagining all those years was you.
他会建起一个小家
He'll build a little home
只为两人存在
Just meant for two
从此我不再流浪
From which I'd never roam
他会是谁  是你吗
Who would, would you
以上的一切
And so all else above
I'm waiting for the man I love
菲利克斯·特纳  跟我一起生活好吗
Felix Turner, would you like to move in with me?
好
Yes.
Yes?
-好吗  -好
- Yes? - Yes!
太好了
Yes! Yes!
无论何时
And so all else above...
我都在等着我爱的
I'm waiting for the man
男人
I love
"这就像身上的定时炸弹
"We are all walking time bombs
不知道什么时候会爆炸"
waiting for whatever it is to set us off."
撑住  我们快到了
C'mon, we're almost there.
"若这篇文章不能使你们警觉
"If this article doesn't scare the shit out of you,
地球以后将不会再有同志的身影
gay men may have no future here on Earth.
我们能否继续生存就看你们有多愤怒"
Our continued existence depends on just how angry you can get."
-四个急诊室都不肯收我们  -进来
- They turned us away from four emergency rooms. - Come in!
我觉得他失去意识了
I think he's lost his mind.
奈德  我能带他去哪
Ned, where can I take him?
把他放在沙发上  我找艾玛
Put him on the couch there. I'll call Emma.
-该死的  -我弄点水
- God damn it! - I'll get some water.
他这样多久了
How long has he been like this?
几个小时了
A couple hours.
我很高兴你问我这个问题
Well, I'm glad you asked me that question.
我怎么看  我知道政府
What do I think? I know that the government
有意忽视这个传染病
is intentionally ignoring this epidemic.
你在指责美国政府
You're accusing the government of the United States
蓄意谋杀所有同志吗
of a conspiracy to murder all gay men?
男同健康危机组织  联合创始人
是的  就是这么回事
Yes. Yes, you can say that.
是  萨拉伯斯  我是
Yes, Sarabeth, I am. Yes.
这是很严重的指责
That is a powerful accusation.
这是传染病  而美国政府
This is an epidemic and it's being ignored
却忽视了它
by the United States government.
-有意的吗  -有意忽视
- Intentionally? - Intentionally being ignored.
这是全国范围的危机
This is a national emergency.
这是传染病  是瘟疫
This is an epidemic. It's a plague.
你不能在国家电视台
You can't go on national TV
指责政府谋杀  奈德
and accuse the government of murder, Ned.
为什么不能
Why not?
因为要靠他们拨款  批准科研项目
Because one day we're gonna get money, research grants.
国会尚未拨出一分钱
Congress still hasn't appropriated a dime.
市长还在说啊说
The mayor's still... on and on!
奈德  对外
Ned, when you go public,
你没有权利代表组织说话
you have no right to speak for this organization
除非事先得到我们的同意
unless we have approved what you have to say in advance.
说到这  其实呢
You know, in point of fact,
你都不属于这个组织
you aren't even an officer of this organization
你根本不该代表我们说话
and you shouldn't be speaking for us at all.
感谢你告诉我这个  迪克
Well, thank you for sharing that with me, Dick.
你为什么觉得面对这次危机
Why do you think the city has been so slow
纽约迟迟不肯接受和应对
to acknowledge and deal with this emergency?
同性权益活动家
你这么说  好像纽约已经意识到了
Well, you're implying that the city has recognized
可是马尔科姆  不是这样
and acknowledged this emergency, Malcolm. It has not.
你为什么认为没有
Why not, do you think?
因为市长是同志  他已经
Because the mayor's gay and he's scared shitless
吓得屁滚尿流  怕自己暴露
out of his panties it'll blow his cover.
-怎么了  -关掉  关掉
- What? - Take it off, get it off.
我们还录吗
Are we still rolling?
我在表达自己的看法  你别插嘴
You can't tell me what to say when I'm speaking for myself.
扯淡  他们都知道你是我们的一员
Bullshit. They all know you're one of us.
把自认为不是同志的人
It is totally and politically incorrect
称作同志  是政治不正确的
to call someone gay who does not self-identify as being gay.
我当然明白这点
I know it's been that way forever,
可是现在情况不一样  我们快死了
but something different is going on here now. We're dying.
市长是你的私人朋友
The mayor, he's a personal friend of yours.
你要他委派给你法官
You want him to appoint you a judge.
跟这里的事有利益冲突吗
Do you have a little conflict of interest going on here?
-我说了  我给他留了便条  -什么时候
- I told you I sent him a memo. - When?
-通过某些渠道  -什么时候
- Through channels. - When?
-他会回复我的  -什么时候
- He'll answer me. - When?!
这个月发生了110宗病例
There's 110 new cases this month!
还是没见到我们的同志市长
Still no meeting with our gay mayor.
没见到他的同志助手
No meeting with his gay assistant.
怎么了  布鲁斯  我让你尴尬了吗
What? Do I embarrass you, Bruce?
是的  没错
Yes. You do.
宝贝  以善待人结果总会好一点
You get more with honey than with vinegar, babe.
汤米  还真没人跟我说过呢
God, no one's told me that one, Tommy.
可不是吗
No, obviously, they haven't.
反正我不信
I never believed that bullshit, anyway.
我们一直在想办法帮助病患
We are in over our heads with the patients we're trying to help.
汤米  你能不能大声念出这份报告给奈德听
Tommy, will you please read this report out loud for Ned?
我们已经训练了25位危机顾问
We have trained 25 crisis counselors
去帮助最新确诊的患者
to help the newly diagnosed
满足他们的所有需求
in whatever needs that they might have.
我们有12个组长每周至少与顾问见面一次
We have 12 group leaders who meet with these counselors
来查看他们所照顾的病人的情况
at least once a week to go over their clients.
有17个心理学家和/或精神病学家
There are now 17 volunteer social workers,
作为志愿社工
psychologists and/or psychiatrists.
我们帮助起草了75份遗嘱...
We helped draw up 75 wills last--
75份  布鲁斯
75, Bruce!
你以前可是斗士
You used to be a fighter once.
-你喜欢待在特种部队里面吗  -我喜欢
- Did you like being in the Green Berets? - Yes. I loved it.
你已经不会抗争了吗
Have you completely forgotten how to fight?
轮不到你教我  咱俩方式不同而已
Don't tell me how to fight. I just fight differently than you.
-你哪里抗争了  -没有吗
- I haven't seen your way yet. - No?
布鲁斯  艾伯特可能要死了
Bruce... Albert may be dying.
你个王八蛋  不许拿他说事儿
You son of a bitch! You say another word about him!
放轻松
Relax.
还有你
And you.
你没资格在这里
You have no right being on this board
除非你给你的市长朋友施压
unless you put pressure on your friend the mayor.
我们一开始让你来
That's why I asked you to
就是为了这个  你心里清楚
join us in the first place and you know it.
-不  我不做  -为什么
- No, no, I'm not gonna do that. - Why not?
不行  我的律师所免费给你提供法律支持
No, you got your free legal work from my firm.
我不要加入你们
I'm not gonna be on your board of directors.
只是为了面上好看  你什么都不用做
It's only for the stationery. You don't have to do a thing.
你在找托词
That is just an evasion.
如果你把它想成是直男的病
If you thought this was a straight disease-- -
不  这跟你是同性恋没关系
Nah, it's got nothing to do with you being gay.
那跟什么有关系
What else does it have to do with?
总有一天  我会让你同意
One of these days, I'm gonna get you to agree
这个国家里超过两千万的男女
that over 20 million men and women in this country
不需要接受心理治疗
don't require the services of a psychiatrist.
我在试着理解
Look, try to understand.
我会看文章  看电视
You know, I read stuff, I see TV.
紧身衣  链条
Guys in leather and chains.
裙子  高跟鞋
Dresses, high heels.
我对自己说"这不是奈德"
I say to myself, "This isn't Ned."
媒体就爱这么夸张
You know the media always dramatizes the most extreme.
你们的形象太糟了
You guys have a dreadful image problem.
所以我们需要你
That's why it's so important
来支持我们
to have people like you supporting us.
你多体面啊
You already have your dignity.
我们得赶快去吃午饭了  还有个重要的会
We better get to lunch. I've got an important meeting.
是吗  有多重要
Do you? How important?
我在请求你的支持
I'm asking for your support.
所有我认为重要的方面  我都支持你
In every area I consider important, you have my support.
我只觉得一件事重要
The only area that I consider important
你却没支持我
I don't have your support at all.
在你的内心深处
In some place deep down inside you,
你还是觉得我病了  对吧
you still think I'm sick, don't you?
我觉得你过得还不错
I think you've adjusted to life pretty well.
-整体来看而已  -我以前看到了你有多不幸福
- All things considered. - I saw how unhappy you were.
你也一样
So were you!
你也去看心理医生了  我们从小一起长大
You wound up going to shrinks, too. We grew up side by side.
我们对爸爸妈妈一样有意见
We both felt the same about Mom and Pop.
我同意
I'll agree to the fact that
我是有很多性格缺陷
I have any number of awful character traits,
但我绝不同意是他们俩的所作所为
but not to the fact that whatever awful things they did to us
把我变成了病态的同志  却把你变成了健康的直男
made me sick and gay while you stayed straight and healthy.
我们对事情的反应不尽相同
We don't all react the same way to the thing.
所以你当了律师  我成了作家
So you became a lawyer and I became a writer.
这只是看世界的方式不同
Well, we have a difference of opinion over theory.
但在你的眼里我是个异类
But your theory turns me into a man from Mars.
我可没这样看你
My theory doesn't do that to you.
你是想说  那么早送你去看心理医生
Are you suggesting I did something wrong
是我的错吗
in sending you into therapy so young?
我又不知道你要看多久的医生
I didn't know you were gonna stay there forever.
在你把我送去之前  我没觉得
I didn't think that I'd had done anything wrong
自己做错了什么
until you sent me there.
本  在这世上你在我心里分量最重
Ben... you mean more to me than anyone in the whole world.
-一直如此  本  你必须得说出来  -说什么
- You always have. Ben, you gotta say it. - Say what?
我跟你一样  说出来  说出来啊
I'm the same as you. Just say it. Say it!
不
No.
你不是
You're not.
我说不出来
I'm not gonna say it.
每次跟你在这个话题上吵输  我都更受伤
Every time I lose this fight, it hurts more.
-我要回家了  -别这样
- I'm going home. - Oh, come on, Lemon.
我还是爱你的
I still love you.
萨拉还是爱你的
Sarah still loves you.
-猫也还是爱你的  -这不是玩笑
- The cat still loves you. - This is not a joke.
我爱你  给你提供法律咨询
You have my love, my legal advice,
还让你帮我理财
my financial supervision.
我不能给你反抗我的勇气
I can't give you the courage to stand up to me
让你觉得可以对我的想法不屑一顾
and say you don't give a flying fuck about what I think.
每个人都多少受到别人的压制
Everybody's oppressed by somebody else in some form or another.
大部分人都知道要奋起反抗
Most of us learn to fight against it
不要在乎别人的眼光  不寻求帮助
despite people's opinions without the help of others.
别再想利用愧疚获得我赞同
And stop trying to wring some kind of admission of guilt out of me.
接受你我生来相同的事实
Agreeing that you were born just the same as I was born
是不会拯救你垂死的伙伴的
isn't gonna save your dying friends.
正是这一点  能救我垂死的伙伴们
That is exactly what is going to save my dying friends.
你说得好像我是敌人一般
You make it sound like I'm the enemy.
我不由得觉得
I am beginning to think
你和你的异性恋世界是我们的敌人
that you and your straight world are our enemy.
我对你非常气愤
I am furious with you!
以及每一个让我觉得爱上同性
And every goddamn doctor who made me feel it
是恶心的事的医生
was sick to love a man.
我试着去理解
I am trying to understand
为什么我们要死了却没人在乎
why nobody gives a shit that we're dying!
五百万买栋房子吗  政府连几分钱都不给
$5 million for a house? We can't even get 27 cents from the city.
已经有四十三个我认识的人死了
I know 43 guys who have died
你却告诉我是我的原因  不是你的吗
and you say it's my cause not yours?
你还是觉得我病态
You still think I'm sick!
我只是一秒钟都忍受不下去了
I simply cannot allow it for one single second longer.
除非你当我和你平等  否则我不会找你
I will not speak to you again until you accept me as your equal!
我们的健康同样重要
Your healthy equal!
我是你的弟弟
Your brother!
对  小心点  小伙子们
Yeah, be careful with that, boys.
-那可是件珍贵古董  -慢慢来
- That is a precious antique. - Easy.
我觉得  我们该把它放到大型沙龙去
I'm thinking we should put that in the grand salon.
我们有地下室吗  应该放那儿去才对
Do we have a basement? That's where it should go.
贝拉  真该把你的臭嘴好好治治
Bella, I think it's time we moved your filthy mouth above ground.
我明天再安排
I'll decorate tomorrow.
都随便扔进去就是了
Just shove it all in there the best you can.
你俩都够了
Okay, knock it off, both of you.
打扰了
Excuse me.
-你好  -你好
- Yes, hi. - Hi.
我叫艾斯特尔
My name is Estelle
我最好的朋友哈维昨晚死了
and my best friend Harvey died last night.
我们形影不离  知道吗
We went everywhere together, you know?
看百老汇的剧  火箭女郎的舞  还一起滑冰
Like Broadway and the Rockettes and ice skating.
他滑起来十分优雅  我却笨手笨脚
He was a beautiful skater. I'm a klutz.
但他不在乎
But he didn't care.
我们曾有过那么多欢乐
We had so much fun.
该死  我想做点什么
Damn it, I wanna do something!
尽管所有我的女同朋友都说
Even though all my lesbian friends say,
"你们男人为我们又做过什么"
"What have you guys ever done for us?"
但我不在乎
But I don't care.
我是为了哈维
This is for Harvey.
拜托了  告诉我  我能有点用处
Please... tell me you can use me for something.
我需要热线电话接线员  你能胜任吗
I need a hotline director. You think you can do that?
-我不知道怎么做  -我也不知道
- I don't know how. - I don't either.
我请你喝杯咖啡吧
Let me buy you a cup of coffee
-然后慢慢聊  好吗  -好
- and we'll figure this out, okay? - Okay.
你想设在这里吗
So, you want to set up here?
对  很好  开始吧
Yeah, this is good. Let's do it.
-你在干什么  -我们是NBC下属的
- What are you doing? - We're from the NBC affiliate.
-怎样  -这里是新成立的男同健康危机组织吗
- So? - This is the new Gay Men's Health Crisis office.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是布鲁斯·奈尔斯  是组织的主席
I'm Bruce Niles. I'm the president.
我可从没同意过
I didn't sign any consent form
你们拍摄我  或是拍摄这里
for you to film me or this establishment.
请关机离开
Please turn it off and leave.
别碰我的摄像机
Hey, now, don't touch my camera.
-谁派你们来的  -一个叫奈德的人
- Who sent you here? - Somebody named Ned.
-威克斯  -太好了  你来了
- Weeks. - Oh, great. You're here.
-有人是同性恋吗  -操蛋的
- Anybody homo? - Son of a bitch.
你好  这东西在录吗
Hello, is this thing rolling?
瞧瞧这个  我们一周内同时登上了这两份杂志
Look at this! We're in both of them the same week.
以及所有的主流电视网
Every major network
现在终于轮到我们的第一间办公室了
and now finally our very first office.
来认识下我们还没出柜的同志主席
I wanna introduce you to our gay president who's in the closet.
他可真帅  你们不觉得吗
And he's so handsome. Don't ya think?
白白浪费了这么帅的封面人物
Such a very handsome cover boy going to waste.
很好  你终于会抗争了  很好  来啊  布鲁斯
Oh, great. Now you fight. Great! Fight, Bruce.
你说得我像个懦夫  但我不是
You made me sound like a coward and I'm not a coward.
知道吗  你没什么可失去的
You know what? You have nothing to lose.
你哥哥为你投资  你有稳定收入
Your brother invests for you so you have income.
你可以随便做同性恋  奈德  但我不行
You can be gay 24/7, Ned, but I can't!
我不行  所以去你的
I can't! So fuck you!
不  去你的  布鲁斯
No, fuck you, Bruce!
上帝啊
Oh, oh, oh. Jesus.
一看到你  我就充满了绝望
When I look at you, I am filled with despair.
一看到你  我就担心我们没办法赢
When I look at you, I worry we're not gonna win.
你觉得这个国家是怎么建成的
How do you think this country was founded?
我还以为我是和保罗·里维尔[爱国志士]一起共事
I thought I was getting started with Paul Revere,
而不是个懦夫
not some coward.
奈德  看着我  看着我
Ned, look at me. Look at me!
看着我
Look at me!
按你的方法来  我们都得死
We are doomed if we do it your way.
-都得死  -他们如果不知道我们是谁
- Doomed! - How are they going to help us
怎么会帮助我们
if they don't know who we are?
要是知道了就不会帮我们了  奈德
They won't help us, Ned, if they do.
你们这群王八
You walking son of b..
别这样
Hey, hey, hey! Hey! Come on.
住手  住手
Come on. Come on.
-真要命  -该死
- Holy shit. - Shit!
好吧  我来接  当然了
Okay, I'll get it, sure.
你好  您是第一个来电的
Hello? Yeah, you are our very first call.
有什么需要帮忙的
How can I help you?
抱歉  你打错电话了
I'm sorry, you have the wrong number.
你们俩都给我控制一点  成吗
You each gotta pull your shit together now, okay?
你也别老闹得小题大做  该死的
And you need to stop being such a fucking drama queen. God damn.
这位是埃斯特尔
This is Estelle.
你们还好吗
Hey. How's it going?
欢迎
Welcome.
那时我能感觉到
I could feel at the time
一切都不得而知
There was no way of knowing
谁知夜晚的落叶
Fallen leaves in the night
将随风飘往何处
Who can say where they're blowing?
如清风般自由
As free as the wind
希望得以真知
And hopefully learning
为何大海之潮
Why the sea on the tide
无路可转
Has no way of turning
远胜于此
More than this
一无所有
There is nothing
我们两人四手  两份收入
Well, we have four hands and two incomes.
再过几年就无福消受了
You're not getting any younger, you know.
远胜于此
More than this
别拿我的年龄说事
All right, let's leave my age out of this.
告诉我一事
Tell me one thing
远胜于此
More than this
-乡下真的很美  -乡下真的很安静
- Very beautiful, the country. - Very quiet, the country.
不不  你敢
No, no. Don't you dare!
我必须得接
I have to.
你又没在你的机器那留这个号码
You didn't leave this number on your machine.
-你答应过的  -你好
- You promised. - Hello?
我的确认为我们需要对市长进行抗议
I do think we should picket the mayor.
是的  我说过  我也坚持我的说法  谢谢
Yes, I said that and I stand by that. Thank you.
你答应过的
You promised.
不不不  等等
No, no, no, no, no. Wait.
"所有不主动站出来的同志
"And every gay man who is unable to come forward
不为自救而抗争的同志
and fight to save his own life
都是在帮助杀害其他的同志"
is truly helping to kill the rest of us."
在你吓得屁滚尿流  并采取行动之前
How many of us have to die before you get scared off your ass
我们还要死多少人  谢谢
and into action? Thank you.
那是谁
Who was that?
好像是"奈德·威克斯教你发脾气"
I hear it's being called the "Ned Weeks School of Outrage."
我跟我们的一个科学记者提起过
I did speak to one of our science reporters.
他怎么说的
What did he say?
结果他也是同志  他不愿意...
It turns out he's gay and he won't...
别对我喊
Don't yell at me.
那些精神病医生  他们肯定做对了什么
All those shrinks, they must have done something right.
瑞塔沃医生
Dr. Ritvo,
-梅洛夫医生  -梅洛夫
- Dr. Malev, - Malev.
吉莱斯皮医生
Dr. Gillespie,
帕蒂医生
Dr. Patty,
马克辛医生  拉维恩医生
Dr. Maxene, Dr. LaVerne.
为什么要用这么长时间
Why does that have to take so long?
你一直在吃甜食
All you ever eat is desserts.
糖分是生命中最重要的东西
Sugar's the most important thing in life.
其他的只是维持生命而已
All the rest is just to stay alive.
该死
Shit.
-怎么了  -该死的董事会
- What? - The fucking board.
他们说我在引起恐慌
They say I'm causing a panic,
我是在炒作自己
that I'm making myself a celebrity.
他们都不愿意出现在镜头前
Not one of them will be interviewed or appear on TV,
于是我就自己上
so I do it all by default.
而你在逐渐成为领袖
And you're becoming a leader.
-你喜欢抗争  -我喜欢抗争  我吗
- And you love to fight. - I like to fight? Moi?
你  对啊
Who, you? Yeah.
你也非常尽兴
And you're havin' a great time.
的确
I am.
真可笑  我从没想做领袖
It's funny, I never wanted to be a leader.
我做得不好
I'm not doing very well.
真可惜我们浪费了这么多时间
It's sad how much time we lost.
我们当时还没准备好而已
We just weren't ready then.
如果我得病了
If I had it...
你会离开我吗
would you leave me?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果我得病了  你会吗
Would you if I did?
不会
No.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我妈分管红十字会地方分会
Because my mother ran the local chapter of the Red Cross.
我八岁时就被她抓去巡回采血车上干活
She put me to work in the Bloodmobile when I was eight.
我就会照顾别人
I'm not programmed for anything else.
奈德  我有事要跟你说
Ned, I have something to tell you.
你终于有宝宝了
You're finally pregnant.
我结过一次婚
I was married once.
你以前从没说过
You never told me that.
是的  我...
Yeah, I...
她说我对她不公平
she said I had been unfair to her,
事实也的确如此
which I had been.
-我有个儿子  -你有个儿子
- I have a son. - You have a son.
-她不让我见他  -你不能见自己的儿子
- She won't let me see him. - You can't see your own son?
你没抗争吗
But didn't you fight?
就是说你很羞愧
That means you're ashamed.
他将来也会的
So he will be, too.
所以我之前才没告诉你  谁说我没抗争了
This is why I didn't tell you. Who says I didn't fight?
奈德
Ned?
那些不像你期望的
What happens to people who
那么坚强的人怎么办
can't be as strong as you want them to be?
我很怕软弱
Weakness scares the shit out of me!
我父亲很软弱  我怕我会跟他一样
My father was weak, and I'm afraid I'll be like him.
他一辈子都没有为什么去抗争过  就这么去了
His life didn't stand for anything and then it was over.
所以我不断抗争
So I fight, constantly.
既然我能做到  我就不明白了
And if I can do it, I can't understand
为什么其他人做不到呢
why everybody else can't do it, too, okay?
等等  你要去哪
Wait, where are you going?
菲利克斯  你上哪去
Felix! Where you going?
菲利克斯  那些话不是有心的  菲利克斯
Felix. I didn't mean anything by that, Felix.
我  很多事我都害怕
I... I... I'm scared of... lots of things.
真的  恐高  我从没告诉过你我怕...
Really. Heights. I never told you I'm terrified of...
怎么了
What?
这东西越来越大
It keeps getting bigger and bigger.
就是不消失
It doesn't go away.
菲利克斯
Felix?
容我问一句  谁是菲利克斯
Who, may I ask, is Felix?
我这辈子还没这么爱过谁
I've never been so in love in my life.
我就没爱过人
Never been in love in my life.
让他明天一早七点半来找我
Tell him to come to see me first thing tomorrow 7:30.
奈德  真该死
Ned, God damn it.
我们该怎么办  从此孤独终老吗
What are we supposed to do? Not be with anybody ever?
可没你想得那么轻松
It's not as easy as you might think.
艾玛  对不起
Oh, Em, I'm sorry.
不用
Don't be.
你怎么会瘫痪的
How'd you get it?
我当年五岁
I was five years old.
一个巴哈马的女人来了我们镇上
A woman from the Bahamas came to our town
她有脊髓灰质炎病毒
carrying the polio virus.
她  跟朋友们住一起
She... stayed with friends.
他们的孩子跟我一起上幼儿园
Their kid was in my kindergarten class.
有四个孩子得了小儿麻痹症
Four of us in that class got polio.
我都穿好万圣节服装
I was all dressed up in my Halloween costume
准备去不给糖就捣蛋了
to go trick-or-treating
我妈妈摸了摸我的额头  让我去睡觉
and my mother felt my forehead, put me to bed.
那晚半夜  我感到整个身体都麻痹了
In the middle of the night, I realized my whole body
除了双臂还能动
except my arms and my hands were paralyzed.
我哭喊着叫妈妈
I was crying out for my mother.
"我动不了了  我动不了"
"I can't move, I can't move."
他们连忙送我就医
They rushed me to the hospital,
医生说我撑不过一天
were told I'd be dead in 24 hours.
我抗争了  活了下来
I fought. I lived.
你上人工呼吸机了吗
Were you in an iron lung?
上了
I was.
然后回家休养
Then I was in bed at home.
我用一个小小的喇叭
I was connected to my class with this little...
跟班里的同学说话
little loudspeaker.
老师要求大家都来看我
All the children were required to visit me.
我们互相问好
We would say, "Hello,"
接着就不知该说什么了
and then not know what to say next.
他们都怕我
They were all terrified of me.
现在也是
Still are.
我吓坏别人了
I scare the shit out of people.
轮椅上的可怕姑娘
The "holy terror" in a wheelchair.
别人也怕我
I'm scaring people, too.
要学会利用
Learn how to use it.
你不需要别人的爱和认可
Don't need everybody's love and approval.
奈德  你的组织是  无价的
Ned, your organization is... worthless.
有分量的人都不肯加入
I can't get anyone important on the board.
我看过300多病人了  就我一个人
I've seen over 300 patients. Me. One doctor.
那些从我们身上赚得盆满钵满的
All these guys who made millions off of us...
时尚  摇滚  电影  房地产界的  都不能指望
fashion, rock, movies, real estate, forget it.
布鲁斯和我一有意见不合
And any time Bruce doesn't agree with me,
-就找董事会投票  -然后你输了
- he puts it to a board vote. - And you lose.
如果没有绝对把握  我不会接受任何信息
I can't pass along sex recommendations
或是接受任何性伙伴
or any information that isn't 100% certain.
科学没有绝对把握
Nothing is 100% certain in science.
反正你也决定不了
It wouldn't matter what you say anyway.
又不怪我  冲我吼什么
Don't yell at me for what I'm not doing.
-你们又干什么了  -不知道
- What the fuck is your side doing? - I don't know!
美国医学协会干什么了
Where's your A.M.A.?
犹太人就爱饿肚子吗
Does being Jewish always make you hungry?
不知道  我不是犹太人
I don't know. I'm not Jewish.
我是德裔的
I'm German.
-大家都以为你是犹太人  -我知道
- Everybody thinks you're Jewish. - I know.
在医学界可以利用这点
In medicine it helps.
你上学的时候一直躺着吗
You stayed in bed the whole way through school?
大学的时候我有了副支架
By college I had my first braces
能走一段距离
and I could walk... a little.
后面就再没有过了
I don't walk so good anymore.
也许是太忙没时间练
Probably because I'm too busy to practice.
你一定要练
You must practice.
就现在  真的
Right now. I mean it.
就现在  来吧
Right now. C'mon.
别刮坏了唱片
Don't scratch my Mathis.
能共舞一曲吗
May I have this dance?
好吧  随你便吧
Okay. You asked for it.
拐杖
My crutches.
我没事
I got it.
没事的
Okay.
我怕他孤单终老
I'm afraid to leave him alone now.
我怕来不及治好他
I'm afraid a cure won't come in time.
我怕自己的怒火
I'm afraid of my anger.
-我不是个好领导  -也不会跳舞  放我回去
- I'm a terrible leader and... - A lousy dancer. Put me back.
脊髓灰质炎也是病毒
Polio is a virus, too.
现在不也有解药了
Nobody gets polio anymore.
他人呢  我们都等了一个半小时了
Where is he? We've been here for an hour and a half.
这群人是谁啊  让我们待地下室里
Who are these people? We're in a fucking dungeon here.
他不能这样
He can't do this to us.
这么对我们我一定要追究他
He cannot do this to us and get away with it.
-开始了吗  -没有
- Did you start? - No.
-好吧  你们好  -好啊
- Okay, God, hi. - Hi.
我的天  坟墓一样
Jesus Christ, what a tomb.
不想让我们抛头露面吗
Do they not want us to be seen above ground?
他人呢  我都晚了一个小时了
And where is he? I'm an hour late.
-一个半  -别对我撒气  小可爱
- Hour and a half. - Don't start on me, lamb chop.
-汤米  你去哪了  -贝尔维
- Tommy, where were you? - I was up at Bellevue.
安排一个垂死的孩子跟母亲见面
Had to put a sweet dying child together with his mama.
他们15年没见了
They hadn't seen each other for 15 years.
孩子没对母亲说过自己是同志
He never told her he was gay.
他不想见她  接连几周都不想
He didn't want to see her. He refused to see her for weeks.
我陪母亲进去时他生气极了
Oh, he was angry when I waltzed in with her.
看母亲抱着孩子真是催人泪下
It was a real weeper. Mama holding her son.
他已经去了
He's dead now.
不好意思来晚了  我是海拉姆·基博勒
I'm truly sorry I'm late. I'm Hiram Keebler.
你好  你们家是做饼干的吗[同名]
Hello. Are you related to the folks who make the crackers?
开玩笑的  我是汤米·博特莱特
I'm kidding. I'm Tommy Boatwright.
奈德·威克斯
Ned Weeks.
布鲁斯·耐尔斯  我是主席
Bruce Niles. I'm the president.
市长要我转达  他十分关心
The mayor wants you to know how much he cares
看到你们肩负的重任
and how impressed he is with how you've been shouldering
他也深表赞赏
your own responsibilities.
-谢谢  -还谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you?
肩负的责任  我们这么办
Responsibilities? Everything we're doing
就是因为你们  我们现在需要帮助
is the stuff you guys should be doing and we need help.
威克斯先生的意思是
What Mr. Weeks is trying to say, sir,
我们应付不过来
is that we're swamped.
每天都接到超过500个紧急求助热线
We're fielding over 500 calls a day on our emergency hotline.
坦白说  我们现在所提供的咨询
And we're providing information that, quite frankly,
本该由政府来提供
the city should be providing, and isn't.
我们需要办公的地方  这里太小了
Sir, we need office space. We have one small room.
每天的人流量超过100人
We have over 100 people calling or walking in and out every day,
而且没人愿意出租
and plus it's real hard
就因为我们是...
when people don't want to rent to us because we're...
那是非法歧视
That's illegal discrimination.
是的  我们都知道
Yeah, we know that to be true, sir.
基博勒先生
Mr. Keebler,
歧视同性恋却不算违法
it is not illegal to discriminate against homosexuals.
为了见市长  我们足足等了14个月
We've been waiting for 14 months to see the mayor.
光是约你在这会面就花了一年时间
It's taken us a year to get this meeting with you.
而且你还晚了一个半小时
You're an hour and a half late.
你有告诉市长传染病的事吗
Have you told the mayor there's an epidemic going on?
-谁说的传染病  -政府
- Says who? - The government.
哪个政府  咱们政府吗
Which government? What? Our government?
-传染病?  -疾控中心已发出声明
- An epidemic? - The Centers for Disease Control declared it.
-在17个月前  -你不可能不知道
- 17 months ago. - You can't not know this!
能别那么歇斯底里吗
Could you please reduce your level of hysteria?
当然可以
Certainly.
纽约  旧金山  洛杉矶
New York City, San Francisco, Los Angeles,
芝加哥  波士顿  丹佛
Chicago, Boston, Denver.
美国的大城市都发现了病例
Every single major American city is now showing cases.
还包括至少25个国家
At least 25 foreign countries.
纽约作为我们的家
But New York City,
作为你们承诺过要保护的城市
our home, the city that you have pledged to protect
这里什么都占大多数
has more than half of everything.
大多数的病例  大多数的死者
Half the cases, half the dead.
死去的人里我认识57个  不想再有了
I know 57 of the dead ones. I don't wanna know any more.
我们什么时候可以见市长
Now, when do we get to see the mayor?
花14个月吃午餐未免也太久了
14 months is a long time to be out to lunch.
-你先等一下  -不  我们不能等了
- You wait a minute. - No, you wait a minute. We can't.
时间可不等人
Time is not on our side.
如果你不带话给市长  我们怎么办
Now, if you won't take word to the mayor, what are we gonna do?
把请愿纹在应召男的鸡巴上
Hire a hunky hustler and send him up to Gracie Mansion
再送到市长府邸吗
with a plea tattooed to his cock?
-科奇市长不是同性恋  -少来了  小姐妹
- Mayor Koch is not gay! - Oh, come on, "Blanche."
听着
Listen.
你们以为我不想帮忙吗
Don't you think I want to help you?
我有个朋友就是因为这鬼东西
I have a friend who is dying of this shit,
正在退役军人医院里垂死挣扎
right now in the V.A. Hospital.
可是你们也知道  这很难办
But it's very tricky. You can see that. It is very tricky.
难办个屁  纽约有100万同志
Tricky, shit! There are a million gay people in New York.
他们跟我都指望着你
A million and one counting you!
告诉你
You know what?
西区有所学校的火炉失火了
A fire goes out in a school furnace on the West Side.
那一天我就接到了3000个电话
I get 3,000 calls in one day.
懂我的意思没
You know what I mean?
要是你们有那么不满
If so many of you are so upset,
为什么就只听到这大嘴巴在讲
why do I only hear from this loudmouth?
问得真好
That's a very good question.
我们这有着50万的同性恋
Okay, so there are half a million gay men in our area.
315例也不算太高
315 cases doesn't seem too high,
还要考虑到这么大的人口基数
considering how many of us... of you there are.
-真是扯淡  -奈德  别
- This is bullshit! - Ned, please.
长官  我知道这很难办
Look, I understand this is tricky, sir.
可是我们需要你的帮助
But we need your help.
我觉得  同时市长也是这么想的
I think, that is, that the mayor thinks
你们反应过度了
you guys are overreacting.
你去告诉那个混蛋
You tell that cocksucker,
他就是个自私冷血的杂种
he is a selfish, heartless son of a bitch!
你是迈克尔·R·马库斯
You are Michael R. Marcus.
卫生署的保密工作可做得不到位
You hold an unsecure job with the city's Department of Health.
换作是我就会提防一下你的朋友
I'd watch out for your friends if I were you.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe that just happened.
米奇  明天我要上"今日秀"
Mickey, I am going on "The Today Show" Tomorrow,
我要告诉他们
and I am telling them,
市长通过威胁你的工作来让我们闭嘴
that the mayor just threatened your job to shut us up.
"今日秀"  你要干什么
"The Today Show"? You're gonna what?
他们不把我们当人看  我们居然容忍他
They are treating us like shit and we're allowing them.
不  政客就这样
No, politicians,
不施加压力就没有回应
the only thing they really respond to is pressure.
他不是说着火就有3000个电话吗
You heard him with his "3,000 West Side calls."
是因为我们的呼声不够壮大
We're not yelling loud enough!
拿好东西
Get your stuff.
-我是汤米  -汤米  我是奈德
- This is Tommy. - Tommy, it's Ned.
尼克死了
Nick died.
操
Shit.
该死的
God damn.
追悼会的安排我晚点再告诉你
I'll call later when I know more about the memorial.
我有个惯例
I have this tradition.
当有朋友离世  我就会这样做
It's something I do now when a friend dies.
把他的名片留存下来
I save his Rolodex card.
我还能做什么
What am I supposed to do?
扔进垃圾堆吗
Throw it away in the trash can?
我不会那么做
I won't do that.
我不会
No, I won't.
那太绝情了
That's too final.
去年  我收藏了五张
Last year I had five cards.
现在我一共有五十张
Now I have 50.
名片做成的墓碑
A collection of cardboard tombstones,
用橡皮筋捆在一起
bound together with a rubber band.
我憎恶这些该死的葬礼
I hate these fuckin' funerals.
真的
I really do.
知道我还憎恶什么吗
And you know what else I hate?
我憎恶追悼会
I hate the memorials.
现在我们社交生活的主要内容
That's our social life now.
就是参加追悼会
Going to these things.
尼克是个舞蹈指导
Nick was a choreographer.
你们了解这个职业吗
I don't know if any of you knew that.
他才刚刚起步
He was just starting out.
没有告诉很多人
He didn't tell a lot of people.
他还想着邀请你们参加
He was waiting to invite you
他在卡内基音乐厅什么的首演
to his big debut at Carnegie Hall or some shit
好让我们都以他为豪
so we could all be proud of him.
他曾经如此优秀
But he was so good.
如此前途无量
He had such promise.
我们失去了整整一代人
We're losing an entire generation.
刚刚起步的年轻人
Young men at the beginning.
就这么去世了
Just gone.
舞蹈指导  剧作家
Choreographers, playwrights,
舞者  演员
dancers, actors.
损失了那么多无法投诸笔端的剧作
All those plays that won't get written now.
再也无缘得见那么多姿态翩翩的舞蹈
All those dances never to be danced.
最后  我只想说我已经不再正常
In closing, I'm just gonna say I'm mad.
我真他妈已经疯了
I'm fuckin' mad.
内心的声音一直在喊  "他们为什么看着我们死"
I keep screaming inside, "Why are they letting us die?"
"为什么没人帮我们"
"Why is no one helping us?"
真相是
And here's the truth.
答案是
Here's the answer.
他们就是不喜欢我们
They just don't like us.
我能战胜它
I'm going to beat this.
我一直是个幸运儿
I've always been lucky.
很好  这才是正确的态度
Good. That's the right attitude.
我以前想在《时报》上班  我成功了
I wanted a job on the "Times," I got it.
我想要奈德
I wanted Ned.
我传染给奈德了吗
Have I given it to Ned?
我不知道
I don't know.
有人得了感冒
One person has a cold,
他的伴侣也许会得  也许不会
sometimes the partner catches it, sometimes not.
有医生说  用安全套就没事
Some doctors are saying it's okay if we use condoms.
我知道
I know they are.
-我们能接吻吗  -菲力克斯
- Can we kiss? - Felix.
你对病菌完全没有抵抗力
You have nothing to fight back with.
你的免疫系统几乎不能叫免疫系统
You have no immune system to speak of.
任何东西都可能感染你的身体
Your body is now open to every conceivable type of infection.
你必须十分小心
You must be careful.
我会全力以赴  你也得这么做
I'm going to do my damnedest, so must you.
我打赌你对所有小伙子们都这么说
I bet you say that to all the boys.
其实呢
As a matter of fact,
是的
I do.
老天
Oh, God.
曾经有个棒小伙
Once upon a time there was a little boy
总想爱上另一个棒小伙
who always wanted to love another little boy.
有一天  他总算找到了这份爱
One day he finally found that love
简直太美好了
and it was wonderful.
我本该戴手套
I'm supposed to use gloves.
本来应该做这  本来应该做那
I'm supposed to do this. I'm supposed to do that.
本来不该吻他
I'm supposed to not kiss him.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我本不该只有四十五岁
I'm not supposed to be only 45 years old
还照顾着一个三十五岁的年轻人
and taking care of a 35-year-old young man
虚弱得像百岁老人  即将死去
who's 100 years old and dying.
艾玛说这就叫起伏
Emma calls it a seesaw.
他好了  他病了
He's fine, he gets sick,
他好一点
he gets better...
又病重一点
he gets sicker.
老天  帮帮我
God help me.
他怕我离开他
He's afraid I'll leave him.
我告诉他  我不会离开的
I told him I wouldn't leave him.
我从没有想过哪怕一秒  要离开他
That I never for one second would think of leaving him.
但他不相信我
But he doesn't believe me.
这样的日子过久了  确实很难相信这样的话
It's hard to believe in much these days.
但我们绝不能失去对彼此的信念
But we must never stop believing in each other.
我糟透了  毫不夸张
I'm a mess. That's what I am.
每天以泪洗面  直到觉得眼泪已经流干
You cry and you cry until you think can't cry anymore
可泪水依旧滑落
and then you cry some more.
不仅是为自己或菲利克斯  也是为了
Not only for yourself or Felix, but for all the little boys
找到此生挚爱的小伙子们
who finally found their other little boys
经受这般历练  终成男人
they've wanted all their lives now that we're men.
男同健康危机组织
G.M.H.C.
我是艾斯特尔  有什么可以帮您的
Estelle speaking. How may I assist you?
有人要写遗嘱
Someone needs a will!
-奈德在哪  我要找他  -他在里面
- Where's Ned? I want to speak to him. - He's in the back.
-给他这个号码  -谢谢
- Here, give him this number. - Thank you.
-男同健康危机组织  -男同健康危机组织
- G.M.H.C. - G.M.H.C.
汤米  我可能找到了四个符合条件的
Tommy, I think I got us maybe four qualified
社工志愿者
social workers to volunteer.
-她们都是女同志  -感谢上帝创造女同
- They're all lesbians. - Thank God for the lesbians.
您的肛门吗
Your anus?
天王星啊[同音]
Oh, Planet Uranus.
感谢来电
Thank you for sharing.
米奇  你怎么不在里约
Mickey, why aren't you in Rio?
我把电话转留言了  你们该休息会
I put the phones on service. You guys should get some rest.
别再有人倒下了
We don't want any burnouts.
晚安  菲尔  谢谢
Good night, Phil. Thank you.
晚安  亲爱的
Night, honey.
-再见  亲爱的  -晚安  亲爱的
- Bye, baby. - Good night, sweetheart.
今天表现很好
Good work today.
好的
All right.
菲尔今天确诊了
Phil got diagnosed today.
米奇  你为什么没在里约度假
Mickey, why aren't you on vacation in Rio?
我本来在里约  格里高利...
I was in Rio. Gregory...
和我本来在里约
and I were in Rio.
我接到了海勒姆办公室的电话
I get a call from Hiram's office
说我今天一早
saying I should be in his
必须立马去他办公室
office right away first thing this morning.
从里约吗  什么大事
From Rio? What kind of meeting?
我去了市政厅  等了海勒姆很长时间
I get to City Hall, Hiram keeps me waiting forever.
终于有专员出来  跟我说
And finally the commissioner comes out and he says
海勒姆不想再见到我了
that Hiram doesn't want to see me anymore.
我真想大叫
I wanted to scream,
"老子两天没睡觉了  你个傻逼"
"I haven't slept in two days, you dumb fuck."
但我没有  反而我说
But I didn't. Instead I said,
"那请问  先生
"Please, sir, then...
他为什么还要让我大老远从里约回来"
why did he make me come all the way back from Rio?"
他说
And he says,
"他也没跟我解释过"
"Oh, I'm afraid he didn't take me into his confidence."
然后就走了
And he walks off.
奈德抨击海勒姆的文章刚刚发表了
Ned's article attacking Hiram just came out.
我不要因为奈德不自爱而丢了饭碗
I'm not going to lose my job because Ned doesn't like himself.
什么意思  米奇
What's that, Mick?
你一直逼我们说我们自己不想说的话
You keep trying to get us to say things that we don't wanna say
我觉得没有足够的朋友
and I don't think we can afford
就不要树立敌人了
to make so many enemies before we have enough friends.
泰瑞·斯伯汀喊来所有朋友
Terry Spaulding is calling all of his friends
从氧气仓里跟他们告别
from under his oxygen tank to say goodbye.
提比·莫勒吸毒自杀
Tibby Maurer took an overdose.
哈尔·沙克特装了假肢
Hal Schechter has got stumps for feet.
弗兰尼·山图扎疯了
Frannie Santuzza's lost his mind!
你能闭嘴吗  别说了
Will you stop it? Just stop!
-米奇  你还好吗  -不好
- Mickey, you all right? - I don't think so.
他们为什么找不出这种病毒
Why can't they find the virus?
亲爱的  这得花时间
Baby, it takes time.
我天天为这个城市写那些...
I work all day for the city writing stuff on...
母乳还是奶粉喂养好
breast-feeding versus formula
染上疱疹不用惊慌的文章
and how to stay calm when you have herpes.
在晚上  我还为
And at night I work on our
《纽约同志会》写通讯和健康专栏
newsletter and our health column for the "Native."
我...我真的受不了了
I just... I can't take it anymore.
各种理论我都写过
I have written about every single theory.
病毒反复感染
Repeated infection by a virus.
休眠病毒的新病征
New appearance by a dormant virus.
一种病毒  新型病毒  古老病毒
Single virus, new virus, old virus,
复合病毒  部分病毒
multi-virus, partial virus,
-潜伏病毒  突变病毒  -淡定  亲爱的
- latent virus, mutant virus... - Take it easy, honey.
不行  还不能忘了性交  口交
No, we mustn't forget about fucking and sucking
接吻  血液  巫术
and kissing and blood and voodoo
毒品  同志吸剂  针头
and drugs and poppers and needles
还有非洲  海地  古巴  黑人
and Africa, Haiti, Cuba, blacks,
阿米巴原虫  猪  还有狗日的天王星
amoebas, pigs, fucking Uranus!
-如果这些都不是传染源呢  -我不知道
- What if it isn't any of them? - I don't know.
伦敦的鼠疫
The great plague of London
是一个水泵里的水引起的
was caused by drinking water from a pump
没人会注意那东西
that just nobody... nobody noticed it.
可能这种病毒就是这样
Maybe it's predisposition or the theory of the herd...
只会感染同志  没有同志就灭绝了
only so many of us are going to get it, then the pool's used up.
如果是单配偶传染呢  布鲁斯  你和我
What if it's monogamy? Bruce, you and I
可能更容易感染
could actually be worse off
因为长期只跟单一传染源接触
because of constant bombardment from a single source...
我们的爱人
our lovers.
或许那些总去浴室的人
So maybe the guys who go to the baths,
建立了最强大的免疫系统
maybe they've built up the best immunity.
我不知道该怎么跟大家说
I don't know what to tell anybody anymore
但大家还在问我
and everybody asks me.
谁对  我不知道
Who's right? I don't know.
谁错  我感觉
Who's wrong? I feel...
我感觉手足无措
I feel so fucking inadequate.
我们该怎么告诉大家  "停下"
How can we tell people, "Stop"?
只是  我不  有可能是因为
It's just... I don't... it might be caused by...
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
我也是这种感觉
That's exactly how I feel.
也许他是对的
And maybe he's right.
这吓到我了
And that scares me.
奈德  你吓到我了
Neddy, you scare me.
你真的觉得总统
You really think the president...
他想让这一切发生的吗
that he wants this to happen?
你真的觉得中情局
You really think the CIA
发动细菌战
has unleashed germ warfare
来杀掉所有杰瑞·法威尔[教会保守人士]不认可的基佬吗
to kill off all the queers that Jerry Falwell doesn't want?
-米克  克制一点  -克制什么
- Mick. Try to hold on. - To what?
我曾经那么爱我的祖国
I used to love my country.
"同志会"收到了封匿名来信
The "Native" received an anonymous letter describing
讲的是国防部的高度机密实验
top-secret Defense Department
在迪特里克港  马里兰州
experiments at Fort Detrick, Maryland...
研制了一种可以摧毁免疫系统的病毒
that have produced a virus that can destroy the immune system.
代号"强硬之手"
Its codename was "Firm Hand."
1978年开始在一批同志身上测试
They started testing it in 1978 on a group of gays.
我之前从来不信这种鬼话
I never used to believe shit like that...
他们要迫害我们
they're gonna persecute us!
他们要撤销我们的医疗保险
They're gonna cancel our health insurance,
他们要把我们送到集中营  隔离我们
they're gonna put us into camps, they're gonna quarantine us.
你觉得我在杀人吗
And you think that I'm killing people?
我说的不是这个意思
That is not what I said.
就是这个意思  你知道你自己说了什么
It is, you know you said it.
我花了十五年时间
I've spent 15 years of my life
来为我们自由的权利作斗争
fighting for our right to be free
还为了能随时随地的做爱
and to make love wherever, whenever.
你却告诉我这么多年来
And you're telling me all those years
为同志争取权利是错的
of what being gay stood for is wrong!
还认为我是凶手
And that I'm a murderer.
我们一直在压抑自己  你都不记得了吗
We have been so oppressed. Don't you remember?
你不知道我们不用躲  没有愧疚  大胆去爱
Can't you see how important it is for us to love openly,
有多重要吗
without hiding, without guilt?
你怎么就不明白
Why can't you see that?
我上到了帝国大厦最顶楼
I went to the top of the Empire State Building.
我送你回家
Okay, I'm taking you home.
可以趁人不注意从上面跳下去
You can jump off from there when nobody's looking.
好了  米奇  我们回家吧  就现在
All right, Mickey, let's go home. Right now.
奈德  我不是凶手  我不是
Ned, I'm not a murderer. I'm not.
我这辈子一直恨自己是同志
All my life I've been hated for being gay,
个子矮
for being short...
还是犹太人
Jewish.
所以你继续  告诉大家
So go ahead, you tell everybody.
告诉大家我们错了  我很抱歉
Tell everybody that we were wrong and I'm sorry.
总有一天  有人会站出来
Someday, somebody's gonna come along
会一刀捅向你  告诉你
and they're gonna stick the knife in you
你抗争的事  你这辈子都是扯淡
and tell you everything you fought for your whole life is shit!
米奇
Mickey!
米奇  起来
Mickey! Get up!
-起来  过来  -没事
- Get up. Come here. - It's okay.
来吧
Come on.
我送你回家  好吗
I'm gonna take you home now, okay?
我不想回家  带我去圣文森特
I don't wanna go home. Take me to St.Vincent's.
好  没事  来吧  走
Okay. That's fine. Come. Let's go.
我们都很累了  听到了吗
Look, we're all real tired, you hear me?
大家走了不少朋友  都很悲伤
We got ourselves here a lot of bereavement overload.
我们是斗士  不是吗
We're the fighters. Aren't we?
-我们是斗  -没错  亲爱的
- We're the fi... - You bet, sweetness.
你还是位英雄
And you're a hero
听到没
You hear me?
不管你知道与否  你都是个英雄
You're a hero whether you know that or not.
你是我们的第一位英雄
You're our first hero.
走吧
Let's go.
你想当主席
You wanna be president?
我只想让菲利克斯活下去
I just want Felix to live.
男同健康危机组织
Gay Men's Health Crisis.
海勒姆  老伙计  现在怎么样
Hiram, old buddy. How's it hanging?
-准备好了吗  -是的
- You ready? - Yeah.
市长找到了个秘密小型基金会
The Mayor's found a secret little fund
能私底下把钱捐给我们
for giving away money secretly.
但我们不能说出钱的来源
We are not allowed to tell anyone where we got it,
要是说出去了  以后一个子都没了
and if we do, we'll never get any more.
-多少钱  -九千美金
- How much? - $9,000.
奈德
Ned.
艾伯特死了
Albert's dead.
他妈妈想在他死前在菲尼克斯见他一面
His mother wanted to see him in Phoenix before he died.
这是上周的事  当时已经很明显了
And this was the last week, when it was obvious.
艾玛同意了  我就带他去了机场
So I got permission from Emma and took him to the airport.
当我们到机场的时候
And when we got to the airport,
飞行员不肯飞
the pilot refused to fly the plane.
我也拒绝下飞机
So I refused to get off of it.
你肯定会为我骄傲  奈德
You would have been very proud of me, Ned.
我们最后换了一个飞行员
So finally we get another pilot
飞机起飞时
and when we take off,
艾伯特失去了理智
Albert just loses his mind.
我不想把事情搞成这样
I don't wanna be in this thing.
-没事的  -我不想把事情搞成这样
- It's okay. - I don't wanna be in this...
-我想离开这里  -不行  艾伯特
- I'm just gonna go. - No, Albert.
我不想...
I don't wanna...
-艾伯特  -叫他坐下
- Albert. - Tell him to sit down.
-对不起  -先生  先生你必须待在位置上
- I'm sorry. - Sir, sir, you have to keep seated.
-坐在这上面  -先生  坐下  你得…
- Sit down up there. - Sir, have a seat. You have to...
不
No!
-先生… -住手
- Sir... - Stop!
先生
Sir!
我们坐下  好吗
We gotta sit down, okay?
他不认得我
He doesn't recognize me.
是我啊  是我
It's me. It's me.
不知道我们要去哪里
Doesn't know where we're going.
-我们快到家了  -我们要去凤凰城
- We're almost home. - That we're going to see his mother
-看他妈妈  -没事的
- in Phoenix... - Nothing.
他变得…
He just becomes...
妈的  能给我块毛巾吗
Oh, shit. Can I get a goddamn towel, please?
当我们到达凤凰城的医院时
When we land in Phoenix and when we get to the hospital
他妈妈准备了一间非常漂亮的房间
where his mother had fixed up the room real nice...
艾伯特却死了
Albert is dead.
医院医生拒绝给他做检查
The hospital doctors refused to examine him
也拒绝在死亡证明上给出死因
and give him a cause of death on his death certificate.
没有死亡证  丧事承办员不能带走遗体
Without the death certificate, the undertakers will not take him.
-警察也不能带走遗体  -伙计  放下来
- And neither would the police. - Come on, man. Pull it down.
最终  某个护理员进来把艾伯特
Finally some orderly comes in and stuffs my Albert
装进了一个超大号垃圾袋
in an oversized glad garbage bag
把他跟其他垃圾扔到了巷子里
and puts him in the alley with the rest of the garbage.
伙计  我帮了你  我把他弄出来了
I did you a favor, man. I got him out.
给我五十块
I want 50 bucks.
-这就是他的骨灰  -对
- Is that all of him? - Yep.
你想要骨灰  三千块
You want him? $3,000.
他走了  他走了
He's gone. He's gone.
走了
Gone.
上帝啊
Oh, God.
"我告诉你们  他们要杀死我们
"I am telling you they are murdering us
"我们要让他们知道
and we are letting them.
"我们快死了"
We're gonna die."
"我们很快就会死了
"We're gonna die very soon,
"除非你们奋起反抗"
unless you get off your fucking asses and fight back."
艾玛等着呢
Emma's in there waiting.
张嘴 就两口  吃点东西
Come on, two bites. Come on, now.
-不吃  -别逼我倒了这碗酸奶
- No. - Don't make me break out the yogurt.
-再吃一口  -跟你哥哥说了吗
- One more. - Have you talked to your brother yet?
我就知道你是这样
I remember that about you.
你不会跟最爱的人说
You don't talk to the people you love most in the world.
你想让我好受点  我不觉得好受
You want me to get better and I'm not getting better
我充满了罪恶感
and I feel so fucking guilty.
你周五约了比尔·布拉斯吃午饭
You have a lunch meeting with Bill Blass on Friday.
挺好的
Fancy.
我要打电话立遗嘱
I'm call with my regrets.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
两个月后我要和你约会
Making a date with you two months from now.
我受邀去耶鲁大学的同性恋周做个演讲
I've been invited to speak at Yale's Gay Week.
我们都要去
And we're going.
还记得我说的舞会吗
Remember how I told you they have those dances there now?
你是我的舞伴
You're my date.
我想要你活下去
I want you to live so much.
我不该那么说的
I'm not supposed to say that.
上帝  再给我们一年时间吧
Oh, please, God. Give us one more year.
我用吃菠菜发誓
I promise I'll eat my spinach.
我比世界上任何人都要
I am taking care of more victims of this disease
更关心生这种病的人
than anyone in the world.
我们有冰冻的血液样本
We have more frozen blood samples,
每种都有更多地数据
more data of every kind,
更丰富的经验
and much more experience.
布鲁克纳医生  政府的立场是这样
Dr. Brookner, the government's position is this.
我们可以帮助病人的资金只有五百万
There are $5 million in the pipeline for which we have received
接到的申请却有五千多万
over $55 million worth of requests.
五百万还不够两千个病人吧
5 million doesn't seem quite right for some 2,000 cases.
政府花了三百万
The government spent 3 million
来调查泰勒诺的七起死亡案
investigating seven deaths from Tylenol.
我们已经做了三年
We're entering the third year.
我们投票决定拒绝你的资金申请
We voted to reject your application for funding.
我想听一下理由
I'd like to hear your reasons.
你所提出的研究方向
The direction of the research you're suggesting
不够精确也没有重点
is imprecise and unfocused.
是吗  是吗
Oh, it is, is it?
你压根就不知道我做了哪些事
You don't know what's going on any more than I do.
你能准确地告诉我  你阻止我的原因吗
Could you tell me precisely why you're blocking my efforts?
布鲁克纳医生  这不是我一个调查员的决定
Dr. Brookner. There are now other investigators.
这不再是你一个人的研究
This is no longer only your disease,
哪怕你以为是
though you seem to think it is.
我以为是吗
Oh, I do, do I?
你要把它带走  是这样吗
And you're here to take it away from me, is that it?
我跟你分享个小秘密  医生
Well, I'll let you in on a little secret, Doctor.
你拿去吧  我根本就不想要
You can have it. I didn't want it in the first place.
看着年轻小伙子死去是好事吗
You think it's a privilege to watch young men die?
我跟你争执什么
What am I arguing with you for?
你连开水都不了解
You do not know enough to study boiled water.
怎么敢跑来评判我
How dare you come down here and judge me?!
我们是穆雷医生
We only serve on this peer
指导的审查小组的一员
review panel at the behest of Dr. Murray.
又一个白痴  还是个未出柜的男同
Another idiot... and, by the way, a closeted homosexual
尽他一切所能掩埋此事
doing everything in his power to sweep this under the rug.
我发誓我从未对外透露任何信息
And I vowed I'd never say anything like that in public.
为什么你的队伍
How does it always happen
都是白痴在充数
that all of the idiots are always on your team?
你怎么能拒绝资助我的研究
How can you refuse to fund my research
或者邀请我加入你们
or not invite me to participate in yours?
国家卫生研究院
Your National Institutes of Health
两年前就收到了我请求拨款的申请
received my first request for money two years ago.
你花了一年打印出申请表
It took you one year just to print up application forms.
距我第一次通报案例三年后
It's taken you three years from my first reported case
你来这看了一眼  我们请求的资助
just to show up here for a look, and the paltry amount of money
跟你们每年得到的40亿相比
you are forcing us to beg for out of the $4 billion
是微不足道的
you now receive each and every year
你们拨款保护的
to protect the health of American people
是屁事都没有的健康人民
won't come to anyone before only God knows when.
法国已经找到可能的病毒了
A promising virus has been discovered in France.
你为什么拒绝跟法国合作
Why do you refuse to cooperate with the French?
为什么不让我们跟法国合作
Why are we told not to cooperate with the French?
好在疾病泛滥  死伤无数时
Just so you can steal a Nobel Prize
你趁机拿个诺贝尔奖吗
while something is being passed around that causes death!
在非洲已经出现女性病例
Women have been discovered to have it in Africa
这显然是会通过异性传染的
where it is clearly transmitted heterosexually.
只是时间的问题
It is only a question of time.
在你有所行动前我们可能都死了
We could all be dead before you do anything.
你要我的数据  我的观点
You want my data? You want my ideas?
我的病人  拿去
You want my patients? Take them!
只要你能为他们做点什么
Just do something with them!
你他妈的说得对  我...
You're fucking right! I am...
不严密  没有目标  而你们都是白痴
imprecise and unfocused and you are all idiots!
针对市长的抗议是你组织的吗
Did you organize that picketing of the mayor?
是
Yes.
-签字呢  -是
- And the signs? - Yes.
你下出戏扮演第一夫人
And your next play is about a First Lady
-好莱坞最出色的口交演员  -是
- who gave the best blow jobs in Hollywood. - Yes.
-这里是我们的完美新办公室  -是
- This place is perfect for our new office. - Yes.
很整齐
So tidy.
来
Here.
我来就行  我来就行
I got him. I got him.
来  扶你到床上去
Come on. Let's get you back to bed.
好
Okay.
来吧
Here you go.
艾斯特尔给你做了菜卷
Estelle made you some stuffed cabbage for later.
这是巴黎的新药
There's this new drug in Paris.
凯斯勒的爱人急着想试
Kessler's lover is flying out to get it.
在这  HPA-23
Here it is. HPA-23.
奈德
Ned.
-他看着很糟糕  -这药
- He looks awful - You this is anything
跟其他药一样没效果吗
or is it just another shit drug like all the rest?
我认为你要做好放手的准备
I think you need to prepare yourself for letting go.
为自己爱的人要抗争到底
You can't stop fighting for the ones you love.
你试过为爱人战斗吗
Haven't you ever had to fight for somebody you love?
汤米  你要开始站出来
Tommy. You gotta start putting yourself out there
让大家见到我所见到的
in a way that everyone else could see what I see.
还真是一出苦情戏
What kind of a fucked-up love scene is this?
是
Yes?
是  女士
Yes, ma'am?
明天四点半
4.30 tomorrow?
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
是他妈的白宫
The fucking White House.
他妈的市长  我被邀请去白宫了
Fuck the mayor. I've just been invited to the White House.
他们准备做点什么了
They're gonna do something!
我只想问
Oh, just so I understand,
我们被瘟疫侵蚀
what exactly does your title mean
总统顾问
你这个顾问能干嘛
in terms of our plague?
我们倾向用正面的措词  否则人民会害怕
We prefer not to use negative terms. It only scares people.
目前已有3339人患病
Well, there's 3,339 cases so far.
1122人死亡
1,122 dead.
我看就是瘟疫  我害怕
Sounds like a plague to me. I'm scared.
你不害怕吗
Aren't you?
你这顾问能干什么来着
What does your title mean again?
我为总统出主意
I come up with ideas for the president
告诉他该做什么不该做什么
about what he ought to be doing and not doing.
好的  了解
Okay, good. Got it.
钱款还没花出
So, the money's there, right? It just hasn't been spent.
法国有了新药
So there's this new drug in France.
为什么卫生研究院没研究看看
Why doesn't the N.I.H. study it?
我想要  我们想要  迫切需要的是
I mean, what I want, what we want, what we desperately need
有个人帮我们省掉这繁文缛节
is for somebody to help us cut through all this red tape.
我可以明确地告诉你  一周之内
I can asure you that not a week goes by
我是不会向总统上报任何事情的
that I don't bring new information and reports to the President.
我们已取得了前所未有的进展
The progress that's been made on this disease is unprecedented.
但这个病会传染啊
But it's contagious.
你不明白吗  这是传染病
Can't you see that because it's contagious,
所以你们得...你们得加快动作吗
you... you have to work faster?
你真的觉得面对这事
Do you really believe that anybody
研究公共政策的学者不管是对民众
in a serious public policy position in their heart of hearts
还是在私底下的会议里
or even in their most closeted meetings
能坦然地说出
says to each other, "Hey, guys,
"这件事大伙别太难过"吗
let's not get too upset about this"?
是的  你的上司
Yes, your boss
就没敢大声地说出"艾滋"这个词
hasn't said the word "AIDS" out loud.
回答我一个问题
Answer me this one question.
这种病  妓女...妓女会染上吗
This shit, can... can hookers get it?
或者说  有过一夜情的人
Or, you know, someone who had a one-night stand?
-当然会  -你没办法证明这一点
- Of course. - You can't prove that.
就我的理解和我读的报告而言
I mean, from what I understand, what I've read,
男女之间普通的阴道性交
female-to-male transmissions through normal vaginal intercourse
好像不太能传染这种病
does not seem to be very efficient.
这种想法显然是错的啊
That simply isn't true.
这是种病毒  又不懂歧视
It's a virus, it doesn't discriminate.
是的  但是...
Yes, but...
这样传染是很难的  不是吗
it's very difficult. Isn't it?
对于直男而言
It's almost impossible for a straight,
就是指那些普通的异性恋
you know, regular heterosexual guy
是很难染上的  我说的对吗
to get it, am I right?
-什么意思  -没有被证实的案例  是吗
- I'm sorry? - There's no documented cases, am I right?
没有一份被证实的案例
There's not a single documented case
显示异性恋男人染上了这种病吧
of a heterosexual man getting it?
无论是通过阴道性交或者是口交
Not from fucking or a blow job?
我没听过这方面的消息
I don't have that information.
太好了  我正是这么想的
Great, that's what I thought.
苏珊  打电话给会场
Susan, call my meeting.
说我大概会迟到15分钟  谢了
I'll be about 15 minutes late. Thanks.
-非常感谢您  -麻烦等等
- Thank you so much. - Wait, please.
-随时和我联系  -先生  等等
- Call me anytime. - Sir. Wait.
大约一亿人有危险
100 million predicted
却没人在乎这件事
and nobody is paying any attention!
二楼需要保安
Hi, I need security on the second floor.
你为什么要坐在地上
Why you sitting on the floor?
我想走过来  结果摔倒了
I fell down trying to get from there to here.
别碰我  天呐
Oh, don't touch me! God.
我讨厌你看着我
I hate it when you look at me.
你饿了吗
You hungry?
我饿了  你呢
I'm hungry, how about you?
我想遍了和我约会的人
I looked in all my datebooks.
睡过的人没有得病的
No one else I slept with is sick.
说不定你才是携带者
Maybe you're the carrier.
没必要这样对对方吧
We don't have to do this to each other.
你会好起来的  菲利克斯
You're gonna get better, Felix.
你已经在好转了
You are.
艾玛说卫生研究院终于开始研究这个了
Emma says the N.I.H. is finally starting research.
-我们得心怀希望  -是吗
- We have to hope. - Oh, do we?
-是的  -真的吗
- Yes, we do. - Do we?
那我怎么才能做到这一点呢
And how am I supposed to do that?
别吃那个鬼东西了
Stop eating that shit!
-给我  -不
- Give it to me. - No!
你得注意均衡补充营养
You know how important it is to watch your nutrition.
我也就能再活个十来分钟了
I have a life expectancy of 10 more minutes.
我想吃什么就吃什么
I'll eat what I wanna eat.
奈德
Ned.
情况越来越糟糕了  知道吗
It's getting messier. Okay?
我不想让你看见
I don't wanna make you see it.
没人能指挥我干什么事
Nobody can make me do anything.
你应该比别人更清楚这一点
You should know that better than anybody.
现在  你是打算坐一辈子吗
Now you gonna sit there on the floor for the rest of your life?
-你没听见我说话吗  -你没听见我说话吗
- Do you hear me? - Do you hear me?
-没听见  -没听见吗
- No! - No?
我试过超过40种疗法了  没听见吗
I've had over 40 treatments. No?
我做过三种...
I've had three...
不对  是四种不同的化疗  没听见吗
no, four different kinds of chemo. No!
我试过三种实验性疗法了
I've had three different experimentals.
艾玛在我身上花费了最多的时间
Emma has spent more time on me than anyone else.
但仍然没有任何效果
And it hasn't done a thing!
你不能强迫这一切好起来
You cannot force the goddamn sun to come out!
我已经厌倦这些争斗了
I am so sick of fighting
厌倦每个人的愚蠢
and everybody's stupidity
盲目  还有愧疚感
and blindness and guilt trips.
你不能吃东西吗  那就别吃
You can't eat the food? Don't eat the food.
我不在乎  你随便吃  我不在乎
I don't care. Take your poison, I don't care.
吃鱼对你有好处
Fish is good for you.
但你可不想吃这个  是吧
Don't want any of that, do we?
也不吃什么绿色沙拉
No green salad!
不吃西兰花  不吃蔬菜
No broccoli! No vegetables!
不吃杂粮面包
No bread with seven grain!
怎么会有人想要喝牛奶呢
Why would anyone ever want any milk?
反正你骨头里有钙了
You might get some calcium in your bones!
你想死吗  菲利克斯
Do you wanna die, Felix?
去死吧
Die!
求你别离开我  菲利克斯
Please don't leave me, Felix.
滚出去  滚出去
Keep out! Keep out!
鸡奸
是
犯罪
滚出去  滚出去
Keep out! Keep out!
基佬
都是
怪物
基佬
都是
怪物
滚出去  滚出去
Keep out! Keep out!
-滚出去  滚出去   -混蛋
- Keep out! Keep out! - Assholes.
男同健康危机组织
Gay Men's Health Crisis.
没错  鹅口疮是真菌感染
Thrush is a fungus, yes.
请告诉他我们会去那里示威
Can you tell him that we'll be picketing there
不怕拘捕或者防暴警察
and not afraid of arrest or police brutality.
-男同健康危机组织  -没错
- Gay Men's Health Crisis. - That's right.
如果市长不见我们
The mayor has four more hours
那在我们进行非暴力抵抗之前
before we carry out our threats of civil disobedience
他还有四个小时
if he doesn't meet with us.
汤米昨天就接到电话了  奈德
Tommy got the call yesterday, Ned.
你为什么没告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?!
你看  我们成功了
You see, it works!
什么时候  什么时候
When? When?
只有两个人能参加会议  奈德
Only two can go to the meeting, Ned.
-什么时候  -汤米是执行理事
- When? - Tommy's executive director.
我要去
I'm going.
理事会已经投票过了  奈德
I polled the fucking board, Ned.
是我写信给市长的  我一定要参会
I wrote that letter to the mayor. That meeting is mine.
我要代表这个组织参会
I am going to go and represent this organization
我生命中的每一分钟都在为之奋斗
that I have spent every minute of my life fighting for
而且这还是在我的客厅里成立的
and that was started in my living room
否则我就退出
or I quit.
你们想让我退出吗
You'd let me quit?
大家让我向你宣读这个
The board asked me to read this out loud to you.
-读什么  -一封信
- Read what? - A letter.
开始读吧
Go on, read it.
我们与理智而有判断力的人们
"We are circulating this letter widely among people
分享这封信
of judgment and good sense.
我们必须扼止你极度膨胀的自负
You are on a colossal ego trip we must curtail.
你反复将恐惧强加于我们
To manipulate fear as you have done repeatedly
对我们来说是野蛮的
is to us, sheer barbarism.
你利用男同志的死
To exploit the deaths of gay men as you have done
在全美国的电视和出版物上大做文章
on television and in publications all over America
对我们来说是残忍的
is to us, an act of vandalism.
在解放多年之后
And after years of liberation,
是你再次将性变得肮脏
you helped make sex dirty again for us...
可怕  还被禁止
terrible and forbidden.
你比任何人
We are more angry at you
都更让我们愤怒
than ever in our lives toward anyone.
我们认为你想领导我们
We think you want to lead us all.
但是
Well...
我们不愿意被你领导
we do not want you to lead us.
根据由威克斯  弗兰克以及莱文斯坦
In accordance with our bylaws as drawn up by Weeks, Frankel,
起草的规章制度
Levinstein,
奈德·威克斯先生将不再担任
Mr. Ned Weeks is hereby removed
男同健康危机组织负责人
as a director of Gay Men's Health Crisis.
我们请求你安静地离开
We beg that you leave us quietly
不要破坏我们
and not destroy us
以及我们无视你反对完成的工作
and what good work we manage despite your disapproval.
即刻生效
Effective immediately."
奈德
Ned.
执行理事不在理事会里  你知道的
The executive director isn't on the board, you know that.
我无权投票
I don't have a vote.
我还能怎么做
What could... what could I have done?
-你没有支持我  -你说错了
- You didn't support me. - That's not true.
你们就是一群送葬者
You're all nothing but undertakers.
这个组织就是个殡仪馆
This whole organization is a funeral parlor.
-奈德  -你们只会关心死人
- Ned... - All you do is take care of the dying.
谁来为生者争取生存的权利
Who's fighting so the living can go on living?
谁来管我的菲利克斯
Who's fighting for my Felix?
汤米  请到楼上来一下
Tommy. We need you upstairs.
我与马塞尔·普鲁斯特  沃尔特·惠特曼
I belong to a culture that includes Marcel Proust, Walt Whitman,
田纳西·威廉斯  亚历山大大帝
Tennessee Williams, Alexander the Great,
以及不计其数的教皇和红衣主教一脉相承
so many popes and cardinals you wouldn't believe.
格林·贝雷特先生  你知道吗
Mr. Green Beret, did you know
促成二战胜利的
that it was an openly gay Englishman
是一位公开出柜的英国人
who's responsible for winning World War II?
他叫阿兰·图灵
His name's Alan Turing
是他拦截了德国人的密码
and he cracked the Germans' Enigma code.
战争结束后他自杀了
After the war was over, he committed suicide
因为身为同志  他受到了无尽的歧视
because he was so hounded for being gay.
他们怎么不在学校里教教这些
Why didn't they teach any of that in schools?
能赢得二战  多亏了一名同性恋
A gay man is responsible for winning World War II!
要是他们这么做了  或许他就不会自杀
If they did, maybe he wouldn't have killed himself
你们也不会如此惧怕自己是个怎样的人
and you wouldn't be so terrified of who you are.
我想这样被大家记住
That's how I want to be remembered.
带领大家赢得战争的人
As one of the men who won the war.
布鲁斯  我知道我是个混蛋
Bruce, I know that I am an asshole.
但请别赶我走
But please don't shut me out.
去吧
Go.
我是你弟弟的恋人
Your brother and I are lovers.
我快死了  想立份遗嘱
I'm dying and I need to make a will.
-请坐  -谢谢
- Please. - Thank you.
我想把所有东西都留给奈德
I want to leave everything to Ned.
我弟弟好吗
How's my brother?
从我一个人的病  到全世界的危机
Well, he blames himself for everything
他都觉得是自己的错
from my dying to the state of the entire world.
还有你俩仍然互不搭理对方
All that plus you two still not talking.
你一定和他一样固执
You must be as stubborn as he is.
我这就给他打电话
I'll call him right away.
好的  他在家收拾行李
Do. He's at home packing.
我们过几天要去耶鲁大学
We're going to Yale in a few days.
参加同志周
For Gay Week.
他说他自己都不敢相信这一切
He says he can't believe it.
他刚进校的时候差点想自杀
He tried to kill himself there when he was a freshman.
我没有太多...
I haven't much...
除了在韦尔弗利特海角上的
except for a beautiful piece of land
有一块美丽的土地
on the Cape in Wellfleet.
奈德不知道这事
Ned doesn't know about it.
这本来是个惊喜
It was to have been a surprise
我们一起远离喧嚣
for when we lived there together
从此在那里幸福快乐地生活下去
or riding away happily ever after.
我还有份保单
I also have an insurance policy,
跟《时报》签的  我是《纽约时报》的
uh... with the "Times." I'm a reporter...
一名记者
for "The New York Times."
这本来是要给我的亲属的
It's meant to come to my next of kin.
我怕他们不会把钱给他
I'm afraid they might not give it to him.
要是把他列为受益人  就必须这么办
Well, if he's listed as a beneficiary, they must.
你聪明得很  别想得那么天真
You're smarter than that. Don't be so naive.
我保证  我会努力确保他们照做的
I assure you, I will fight to make sure that they do.
就等你这句话呢
I was hoping you'd say that.
菲利克斯...
Felix...
真希望我们能早点见面
I wish we'd met sooner.
我该穿白色的衣服
I should be wearing something white.
你穿着呢  亲爱的
You are, honey.
应该...应该是派瑞·艾力斯
It should... it should be something
为我量身定做的
Perry Ellis ran up for me personally.
奈德
Ned?
你想办法再去争取
You find a way to fight again.
我会的
I will.
艾玛  艾玛...
Emma. Emma...?
我们能...我们能开始了吗
Could we... could we start now, please?
"我们在上帝的注视下聚集于此
"We are gathered here in the sight of God
来见证这两位男人的结合
to join together these two men.
他们深爱对方...
They love each other very much and...
想在亲友面前
want to be married in the presence of their family
永结同心
and friends.
没人反对
I see no objection.
菲利克斯·特纳  你愿意
Do you, Felix Turner,
-接受奈德·威克斯...  -是亚历山大
- take Ned Weeks...  - Alexander. Yeah.
作为你的...
To be your...
我的真爱
My great true love.
我愿意
I do.
我愿意  我愿意
I do. I do.
我愿意
I do.
我愿意  我愿意
I do. I do.
我是汤米
This is Tommy.
谢谢你告诉我
Thanks for letting me know.
耶鲁同志周
1985年9月17日  罗纳德·里根总统首次在公开场合提及艾滋病
在一次记者招待会上  他称艾滋病研究是"重中之重"
里根提议政府拨款资助研究  1986年  在艾滋病方面的开销减少了11%
截止1986年底  共有24559人死亡
1981年至今  全球共有超过3600万人死于艾滋病及其并发症
每天  全球有超过6000人感染艾滋病毒